1
00:00:11,160 --> 00:00:13,880
Plato wanted to reach true knowledge,

2
00:00:13,960 --> 00:00:15,880
the essence of things.

3
00:00:16,120 --> 00:00:18,760
It's said that he once defined man as essentially

4
00:00:18,840 --> 00:00:20,920
a "Two-legged animal without feathers".

5
00:00:21,040 --> 00:00:22,680
But he had to change the definition,

6
00:00:22,760 --> 00:00:25,040
because Diogenes plucked the feathers from a hen.

7
00:00:26,560 --> 00:00:27,600
Go for it!

8
00:00:27,720 --> 00:00:28,760
Let's see.

9
00:00:28,840 --> 00:00:31,400
Do you know where does the phrase "Platonic love" Come from?

10
00:00:31,480 --> 00:00:32,680
Let's see, who knows?

11
00:00:32,760 --> 00:00:33,960
"Platonic love." You!

12
00:00:34,040 --> 00:00:38,160
From Plato. It means an ideal, impossible love.

13
00:00:38,240 --> 00:00:39,640
Yes, popularly that's it.

14
00:00:39,720 --> 00:00:42,920
But that's a bad interpretation of Plato's concept of love.

15
00:00:43,120 --> 00:00:44,120
For him, love

16
00:00:44,200 --> 00:00:47,200
is the impulse that leads to the knowledge of the idea of beauty.

17
00:00:58,600 --> 00:01:01,800
Sweetie, will you come home this afternoon?

18
00:01:06,800 --> 00:01:07,800
We'll see.

19
00:01:08,080 --> 00:01:09,540
One thing is the sensible

20
00:01:09,540 --> 00:01:12,240
world and quite another is the world of ideas.

21
00:01:16,640 --> 00:01:18,080
You are awaited at the principal's office.

22
00:01:21,480 --> 00:01:22,600
Hello. Come in.

23
00:01:23,800 --> 00:01:24,800
Come in.

24
00:01:26,800 --> 00:01:29,560
Eugeni went to teach Iván Blasco at his house,

25
00:01:29,640 --> 00:01:30,560
but Iván's mother told him

26
00:01:30,570 --> 00:01:32,320
that someone named Merli had came the day before.

27
00:01:32,400 --> 00:01:35,880
-Yes. I went to help him. -What do you think I was going to do?

28
00:01:35,960 --> 00:01:38,600
Sorry, but I don't believe your altruism.

29
00:01:38,680 --> 00:01:41,360
-Merli, please. -You are ridiculous.

30
00:01:41,480 --> 00:01:44,440
Just like when you told the kids that you are homeless

31
00:01:44,520 --> 00:01:45,600
and don't have money.

32
00:01:45,680 --> 00:01:47,720
It's better than insulting them.

33
00:01:47,800 --> 00:01:48,660
Enough, Merli, enough.

34
00:01:48,660 --> 00:01:50,560
You brought yourself into a very delicate topic.

35
00:01:50,640 --> 00:01:51,640
Iván has agoraphobia.

36
00:01:51,720 --> 00:01:53,920
-All I did was... -No! You know what you should do?

37
00:01:54,000 --> 00:01:55,560
-What? -And even more if you are broke?

38
00:01:55,640 --> 00:01:57,480
Keep your job. That's what you should do.

39
00:01:58,960 --> 00:02:02,760
Eugeni will officially start teaching Iván this afternoon.

40
00:02:03,040 --> 00:02:05,520
-I hope you keep that in mind. -I'll keep that in mind.

41
00:02:06,480 --> 00:02:07,520
I hope so.

42
00:02:14,640 --> 00:02:15,640
Merli,

43
00:02:16,200 --> 00:02:17,760
you must be at the service of the institute,

44
00:02:17,840 --> 00:02:19,200
not the institute at your service.

45
00:02:20,200 --> 00:02:22,720
Do me a favor and do not skip any more rules.

46
00:02:28,720 --> 00:02:30,000
Thank you, Santi.

47
00:02:48,960 --> 00:02:51,160
Who wants to cheat in the literary contest?

48
00:03:25,680 --> 00:03:27,400
What do you mean by cheating?

49
00:03:28,280 --> 00:03:29,280
One moment, one moment!

50
00:03:29,360 --> 00:03:30,360
First of all, kids,

51
00:03:30,440 --> 00:03:33,440
first of all: is anyone taking part in the literary contest?

52
00:03:38,800 --> 00:03:41,240
Very well. I propose writing a poem among us.

53
00:03:41,880 --> 00:03:44,760
We could base it on Plato's idea of love.

54
00:03:44,960 --> 00:03:48,160
Obviously we won't tell anyone outside this class.

55
00:03:49,360 --> 00:03:51,200
It will be signed by one of you,

56
00:03:51,280 --> 00:03:53,320
who will be the one receiving the prize in case of winning.

57
00:03:53,400 --> 00:03:54,840
One wins, we all win.

58
00:03:55,360 --> 00:03:56,360
Cool, cool!

59
00:03:56,440 --> 00:03:58,360
Great! How much is the prize?

60
00:03:58,440 --> 00:04:00,280
Don't get all fired up. A bunch of books.

61
00:04:00,640 --> 00:04:01,960
The important thing is to participate.

62
00:04:02,040 --> 00:04:05,280
No, no. The important thing is trying to do something together

63
00:04:05,360 --> 00:04:08,760
and abandoning this paradisiacal pastoral life.

64
00:04:10,680 --> 00:04:13,160
What is he saying? This man is a nutcase!

65
00:04:13,240 --> 00:04:15,480
-Tell me, Joan. -No, the idea is fine.

66
00:04:15,560 --> 00:04:17,120
-Ah, well. Thank you. -But...

67
00:04:17,320 --> 00:04:18,720
isn't that breaking the rules?

68
00:04:18,960 --> 00:04:21,840
Joan, Joan, my friend. Joa, please.

69
00:04:21,920 --> 00:04:23,680
Can't you do something wrong once in your life?

70
00:04:23,760 --> 00:04:26,120
-Joan is right! -Come on, dammit, it's fun.

71
00:04:26,280 --> 00:04:29,440
When was it that people your age only did whatever was allowed?

72
00:04:29,720 --> 00:04:31,720
A very good reflection, Merli!

73
00:04:31,800 --> 00:04:33,480
Remind me to give you an extra point in the test.

74
00:04:35,800 --> 00:04:37,800
Guys, seriously. Let's do it!

75
00:04:38,040 --> 00:04:39,170
We will win. In addition,

76
00:04:39,170 --> 00:04:41,000
Vilaseca, you are really good at poetry.

77
00:04:41,760 --> 00:04:43,800
-A little. Not that much. -Man!

78
00:04:43,880 --> 00:04:45,840
Really, Marc? Do you read poetry?

79
00:04:46,240 --> 00:04:48,400
I learned a Shakespeare sonnet for our drama class.

80
00:04:48,600 --> 00:04:50,440
Man, come on. Spit it out!

81
00:04:50,520 --> 00:04:51,520
Recite it, man!

82
00:04:51,600 --> 00:04:54,320
-Come on, come on. Say it. -Quiet, you all.

83
00:04:59,160 --> 00:05:00,720
"Being your slave,

84
00:05:00,800 --> 00:05:03,720
what should I do but tend upon the hours and times

85
00:05:03,800 --> 00:05:05,200
of your desire?

86
00:05:05,280 --> 00:05:09,160
I have no precious time at all to spend,

87
00:05:09,240 --> 00:05:12,280
nor services to do, till you require."

88
00:05:18,480 --> 00:05:19,480
Yes, sir!

89
00:05:20,560 --> 00:05:21,640
Bravo!

90
00:05:23,760 --> 00:05:27,280
Pol! Hey, Pol! Charge your batteries or I'll change my favorite.

91
00:05:27,360 --> 00:05:30,600
Bullshit! Merli, now I'll show you that I'm your favorite.

92
00:05:30,960 --> 00:05:33,600
What do you think of writing an erotic poem?

93
00:05:34,800 --> 00:05:35,800
Cool!

94
00:05:35,880 --> 00:05:36,880
I like it!

95
00:05:37,840 --> 00:05:41,480
I want proposals, verses, ideas. Come on, go for it! Inspiration!

96
00:05:47,800 --> 00:05:50,320
"Paradisiacal pastoral life"... I can't find it, man.

97
00:05:50,400 --> 00:05:53,000
It means that we are lazy and we don't strive.

98
00:05:53,080 --> 00:05:55,120
That's why he wants to turn us on with the porn poem.

99
00:05:55,200 --> 00:05:58,320
Merli is... I love him. The idea of cheating is...

100
00:05:58,560 --> 00:05:59,920
I want more hours of Merli! He's amazing.

101
00:06:00,000 --> 00:06:01,960
Keep calm! Keep calm, Geri, keep calm.

102
00:06:02,320 --> 00:06:04,840
The girls freaked out when I recited Shakespeare!

103
00:06:04,920 --> 00:06:06,040
-What are you saying, man? -Man...

104
00:06:06,120 --> 00:06:07,480
-Come on! -You say to a girl,

105
00:06:07,560 --> 00:06:09,200
"I paint my age with the beauty of your days."

106
00:06:09,280 --> 00:06:10,520
-So what? -Then you fuck her!

107
00:06:10,600 --> 00:06:12,080
-No way! -They'll think you're a fag, man!

108
00:06:12,160 --> 00:06:13,360
Exactly!

109
00:06:13,440 --> 00:06:15,520
No, no! You have to offer girls something else.

110
00:06:15,720 --> 00:06:17,080
There's a lot of competition.

111
00:06:17,160 --> 00:06:19,120
Yes, as Merli. He must fuck a lot!

112
00:06:19,200 --> 00:06:20,000
Yeah, look who's talking!

113
00:06:20,000 --> 00:06:21,480
The one who spends every afternoon at Berta's.

114
00:06:21,560 --> 00:06:25,080
Yeah. But visits to her mother's hairdresser's are over.

115
00:06:26,960 --> 00:06:28,240
Have you broken up?

116
00:06:28,520 --> 00:06:32,040
No, no. Not yet, but... She's so annoying, man.

117
00:06:32,320 --> 00:06:34,280
All the time, "Love! My love! Sweetie."

118
00:06:34,840 --> 00:06:36,040
She's a pain.

119
00:06:41,400 --> 00:06:42,600
Hi, Laia!

120
00:06:45,960 --> 00:06:47,480
That one is so hot!

121
00:06:47,640 --> 00:06:49,280
She's a bombshell!

122
00:06:49,680 --> 00:06:50,840
I'd fuck her right here!

123
00:06:51,200 --> 00:06:55,200
Yes, but... she's older. She must be 25 or so.

124
00:06:58,080 --> 00:06:59,280
All for the better!

125
00:07:01,040 --> 00:07:02,360
Wake up once and for all!

126
00:07:06,120 --> 00:07:10,880
Laia. Do you know if there's faculty meeting next week?

127
00:07:11,080 --> 00:07:14,440
No. The literary contest committee will have a meeting.

128
00:07:14,520 --> 00:07:17,000
Ah, the pageant. Did many students apply?

129
00:07:17,160 --> 00:07:19,240
Not many. 20 or 30, maybe.

130
00:07:20,200 --> 00:07:22,400
Listen, we should not talk here.

131
00:07:22,720 --> 00:07:24,000
Albert could see us.

132
00:07:24,080 --> 00:07:26,120
We are coworkers. What's weird about this?

133
00:07:26,320 --> 00:07:29,680
-Please, don't insist. -You have to look normal, Laia.

134
00:07:30,200 --> 00:07:33,320
How do you want me to be normal? I cheated on him.

135
00:07:33,400 --> 00:07:37,120
Let's see. To me, infidelity exists only if there is infatuation.

136
00:07:37,200 --> 00:07:39,600
And this is not the case. You're not in love with me.

137
00:07:39,880 --> 00:07:41,240
It was sex, period.

138
00:07:41,680 --> 00:07:43,760
But you liked it, didn't you?

139
00:07:44,560 --> 00:07:46,120
Do you hear yourself when you talk?

140
00:07:47,320 --> 00:07:49,400
Where do you get this blatant self-assurance?

141
00:07:51,280 --> 00:07:52,320
Do you know what I say?

142
00:07:52,640 --> 00:07:54,560
There will be nothing else between us.

143
00:07:58,320 --> 00:07:59,440
No.

144
00:08:04,360 --> 00:08:07,880
-I love you. -Thank you.

145
00:08:19,040 --> 00:08:20,320
Will we meet today?

146
00:08:23,760 --> 00:08:25,640
I have to pick up my grandmother at the day care center.

147
00:08:26,200 --> 00:08:28,200
My brother works, so I have to do it every afternoon.

148
00:08:28,360 --> 00:08:30,600
-Can't your father go? -Yeah, sure.

149
00:08:31,240 --> 00:08:32,320
I have to go.

150
00:08:33,000 --> 00:08:34,360
You hadn't told me.

151
00:08:35,640 --> 00:08:36,960
I'm telling you now.

152
00:08:37,840 --> 00:08:40,160
In addition, I want to take the bike to the repair shop.

153
00:08:40,480 --> 00:08:42,440
If you bring the bike, we can meet.

154
00:08:42,760 --> 00:08:44,220
Today my mother's hairdresser's is closed.

155
00:08:44,220 --> 00:08:45,240
If you want, we can go there.

156
00:08:48,800 --> 00:08:50,360
Berta, we're fine this way.

157
00:08:52,080 --> 00:08:53,440
We meet here.

158
00:08:56,560 --> 00:08:58,120
Are you breaking up with me?

159
00:08:59,080 --> 00:09:01,080
Don't be upset. We're friends, aren't we?

160
00:09:04,080 --> 00:09:05,660
-Dammit! Are you going to cry now?

161
00:09:05,670 --> 00:09:07,400
-Not because of that. Leave me alone!

162
00:09:08,320 --> 00:09:09,360
What's wrong?

163
00:09:11,560 --> 00:09:13,360
Have you argued with your mother again?

164
00:09:17,320 --> 00:09:20,280
I want to be with you because I'm very scared and I want company.

165
00:09:23,800 --> 00:09:25,160
I didn't get my period.

166
00:09:26,360 --> 00:09:27,680
What?

167
00:09:28,560 --> 00:09:30,800
Berta, what the hell do you mean by you didn't get your period?

168
00:09:30,880 --> 00:09:32,920
-Explain it to me right now! -I don't know.

169
00:09:33,840 --> 00:09:34,840
You don't know?

170
00:09:34,920 --> 00:09:36,800
-It's impossible! -Maybe the condom broke! I don't know!

171
00:09:39,680 --> 00:09:41,000
Damn it!

172
00:09:56,520 --> 00:09:58,200
Iván, open. Come on.

173
00:10:02,400 --> 00:10:04,120
Don't pretend you are not there.

174
00:10:04,520 --> 00:10:06,200
Your mother will be upset if you don't open.

175
00:10:09,240 --> 00:10:10,240
Iván!

176
00:10:13,560 --> 00:10:14,880
Iván!

177
00:10:18,400 --> 00:10:20,800
Iván, are you stupid or what?

178
00:10:38,800 --> 00:10:41,200
Fantastic. You have done it very well. Congratulations.

179
00:10:41,800 --> 00:10:43,880
Listen. I can't teach you today,

180
00:10:43,960 --> 00:10:47,280
because I'm not officially your tutor. Understand?

181
00:10:47,800 --> 00:10:50,800
It would be unethical for me to teach you

182
00:10:50,880 --> 00:10:53,360
when your teacher still is Eugeni Bosc.

183
00:10:54,320 --> 00:10:55,520
If you want me to come,

184
00:10:55,880 --> 00:10:58,520
you have to tell your mother that you'll only work with me.

185
00:10:59,800 --> 00:11:00,920
Okay?

186
00:11:01,680 --> 00:11:03,000
What do you think?

187
00:11:03,680 --> 00:11:06,520
-No, girl. I made it up. -Wait. Hold it.

188
00:11:06,600 --> 00:11:07,960
I don't get it. What did you say to Pol?

189
00:11:08,160 --> 00:11:11,240
Well, he freaked out when I told him I didn't get my period.

190
00:11:11,680 --> 00:11:14,200
And now he believes I might be pregnant.

191
00:11:14,480 --> 00:11:15,840
That I'm carrying a baby inside.

192
00:11:18,160 --> 00:11:21,440
It's a lie. So what? He told me he was in love with me.

193
00:11:22,760 --> 00:11:24,920
I had told you he says it to all the girls.

194
00:11:26,040 --> 00:11:27,200
What was his reaction?

195
00:11:29,480 --> 00:11:30,840
You should have seen his face.

196
00:11:31,960 --> 00:11:33,520
Someday, you will have to tell him the truth.

197
00:11:34,040 --> 00:11:35,680
When I get tired. I can be patient.

198
00:11:36,400 --> 00:11:39,800
-But he must be terrified. -If you tell him...

199
00:11:40,160 --> 00:11:42,080
No, I won't. I swear.

200
00:11:43,320 --> 00:11:44,480
I swear.

201
00:11:45,800 --> 00:11:47,680
Can you help me with the Grammar assignment this afternoon?

202
00:11:48,600 --> 00:11:50,560
I'm going shopping with my mother.

203
00:11:50,920 --> 00:11:53,000
Great. Going to the market with your mom is more important

204
00:11:53,080 --> 00:11:55,000
than helping a friend with work, right?

205
00:11:57,440 --> 00:12:00,640
Okay. And you have to help me with the erotic poem.

206
00:12:00,800 --> 00:12:02,080
-Okay. -Okay.

207
00:12:05,880 --> 00:12:08,640
But what do they teach those directors in drama school?

208
00:12:08,720 --> 00:12:12,480
Now he wants me to bring home a machine-gun to...

209
00:12:12,560 --> 00:12:14,480
to feel it. To...

210
00:12:15,120 --> 00:12:16,800
To embrace it.

211
00:12:17,560 --> 00:12:21,000
I told him, "Get up here and you'll see Canterbury."

212
00:12:22,080 --> 00:12:23,600
Oh, what a guy. Pour me.

213
00:12:24,560 --> 00:12:27,080
Did you know your son wants to cheat in the literary contest?

214
00:12:28,440 --> 00:12:31,640
We're writing an erotic poem that will be signed only by one.

215
00:12:31,960 --> 00:12:33,880
-What a great idea! -No! It's not a great idea!

216
00:12:34,080 --> 00:12:35,840
-It's a "Merlinada." -Don't go to class.

217
00:12:36,680 --> 00:12:38,080
I never miss class.

218
00:12:38,160 --> 00:12:41,600
Look, I give you permission to miss all of Eugeni Bosc's classes.

219
00:12:42,320 --> 00:12:44,920
All teachers are bad, except you, right?

220
00:12:45,320 --> 00:12:47,400
You're the coolest, because you encourage us to cheat.

221
00:12:48,560 --> 00:12:49,680
How boring.

222
00:12:50,160 --> 00:12:53,000
It's pathetic! You act as if you were a teenager of...

223
00:12:53,960 --> 00:12:55,250
-I don't even know how old you are!

224
00:12:55,250 --> 00:12:56,400
-You don't have to do anything.

225
00:12:56,840 --> 00:12:59,720
Start thinking about verses. I'll ask for them in class tomorrow.

226
00:13:50,520 --> 00:13:51,520
Miriam.

227
00:13:52,360 --> 00:13:54,720
How are you? You wanted to talk to me? Let's go to my office.

228
00:13:54,800 --> 00:13:56,320
No, I have to run back to work.

229
00:13:56,880 --> 00:13:59,840
I wanted to tell you that I'm worried about Iván.

230
00:14:00,240 --> 00:14:01,740
I'm sorry. I apologize for

231
00:14:01,740 --> 00:14:04,240
the trouble the Philosophy teacher created.

232
00:14:04,480 --> 00:14:07,440
It was a misunderstanding. How was yesterday with Eugeni?

233
00:14:07,760 --> 00:14:09,480
-There was no class. -There wasn't? Why not?

234
00:14:09,760 --> 00:14:11,120
Iván did not open the door.

235
00:14:11,600 --> 00:14:13,520
I guess that was because of his illness.

236
00:14:13,840 --> 00:14:16,880
Well. Those psychological questions are delicate.

237
00:14:16,960 --> 00:14:18,080
I suppose that when he talks to the psychologist...

238
00:14:18,160 --> 00:14:20,840
-No, no. He doesn't want a psychologist. -He doesn't?

239
00:14:21,520 --> 00:14:25,120
-He wants the other teacher. Merli. -Merli?

240
00:14:27,040 --> 00:14:28,480
-Yes. -He wants him.

241
00:14:31,640 --> 00:14:33,720
We'll have to convince him, because...

242
00:14:34,320 --> 00:14:36,800
the volunteer teacher is Eugeni.

243
00:14:36,880 --> 00:14:38,000
You should understand

244
00:14:38,080 --> 00:14:39,050
that I will not allow my

245
00:14:39,050 --> 00:14:40,840
child to study with someone he doesn't like.

246
00:14:42,240 --> 00:14:44,960
I want him to be cured. And to be happy.

247
00:14:46,680 --> 00:14:48,120
I understand, Miriam. I understand, but...

248
00:14:48,200 --> 00:14:50,080
Iván is all I have in this life.

249
00:14:50,960 --> 00:14:52,760
Don't know what's so special about Merli,

250
00:14:52,760 --> 00:14:54,520
but I want him to take care of my child.

251
00:15:14,480 --> 00:15:15,760
You are very smart.

252
00:15:18,120 --> 00:15:19,280
How did you manage?

253
00:15:20,680 --> 00:15:23,800
What strategy did you use to convince Iván's mother

254
00:15:24,080 --> 00:15:25,880
that it should be you the one to teach her son?

255
00:15:25,960 --> 00:15:27,560
-No. No strategy. -No?

256
00:15:27,640 --> 00:15:31,160
She knows well that I have more time to devote to him.

257
00:15:31,240 --> 00:15:33,120
I don't work full-time, so...

258
00:15:35,120 --> 00:15:36,360
You think I'm an idiot.

259
00:15:36,370 --> 00:15:38,760
But little by little you will figure it out.

260
00:15:43,600 --> 00:15:46,320
Apparently, Iván only wants you.

261
00:15:47,760 --> 00:15:48,800
Intriguing.

262
00:15:49,080 --> 00:15:51,120
He is the smart one, not me.

263
00:15:52,040 --> 00:15:55,240
You've convinced him. I don't know how, but you did it.

264
00:15:57,200 --> 00:15:58,960
Merli, enough with your manipulations.

265
00:16:04,480 --> 00:16:06,040
You will teach Iván.

266
00:16:06,480 --> 00:16:10,000
And you will compensate Eugeni by overseeing detention for him.

267
00:16:10,080 --> 00:16:11,640
-Just so you know. -That cannot be done.

268
00:16:11,720 --> 00:16:12,720
You can't do it?

269
00:16:12,800 --> 00:16:15,440
Do you want me to call the school board? I don't care.

270
00:16:15,800 --> 00:16:17,000
What? Should I call?

271
00:16:24,520 --> 00:16:27,960
I've written two verses. Somewhat trashy, I think.

272
00:16:28,840 --> 00:16:30,520
It's just me, or my father is crazy?

273
00:16:30,920 --> 00:16:32,160
I think he is funny.

274
00:16:35,720 --> 00:16:36,840
He didn't even say hello.

275
00:16:36,960 --> 00:16:39,440
Leave him alone, he's got problems. Nothing to do with you.

276
00:16:39,680 --> 00:16:41,160
-What happened? -Nothing.

277
00:16:41,920 --> 00:16:44,680
-No, come on. What? Tell me. -It's nothing.

278
00:16:44,880 --> 00:16:46,400
-Come on! -I can't. I can't!

279
00:16:46,480 --> 00:16:48,240
You haven't told me who you are in love with.

280
00:16:48,880 --> 00:16:50,560
I'll tell you, but you first.

281
00:16:53,680 --> 00:16:56,280
-Pol has broken up with Berta. -Really?

282
00:16:57,400 --> 00:16:59,840
And he's scared because he thinks she is pregnant.

283
00:17:00,520 --> 00:17:02,120
And why did she do that?

284
00:17:02,600 --> 00:17:06,080
She wanted to scare him, because he wanted to break up.

285
00:17:06,800 --> 00:17:08,200
I don't understand why you are her friend.

286
00:17:08,640 --> 00:17:10,040
She makes you follow her, and you...

287
00:17:10,560 --> 00:17:11,680
Like a puppy.

288
00:17:14,040 --> 00:17:16,720
You always get jealous of Berta.

289
00:17:17,040 --> 00:17:18,160
-Me? -Yeah.

290
00:17:18,720 --> 00:17:20,640
I might think you're in love with me.

291
00:17:22,640 --> 00:17:24,600
I've written some verses for the poem, too.

292
00:17:24,800 --> 00:17:25,960
-Really? -Yeah.

293
00:17:34,840 --> 00:17:36,400
Will you read that to your father?

294
00:17:37,880 --> 00:17:38,920
Very well.

295
00:17:45,600 --> 00:17:46,800
-Hello, Merli. -Hey.

296
00:17:47,880 --> 00:17:49,840
-Have you seen Eugeni? -I have not.

297
00:17:50,480 --> 00:17:52,070
You haven't? I have to talk to him.

298
00:17:52,070 --> 00:17:53,720
He asked me an article for his blog.

299
00:17:54,000 --> 00:17:56,480
Oh, nice. That will give you prestige.

300
00:18:00,400 --> 00:18:01,520
Hi.

301
00:18:03,280 --> 00:18:04,840
Toni was looking for you.

302
00:18:05,320 --> 00:18:06,720
Toni? You didn't tell him that you and I...?

303
00:18:06,800 --> 00:18:08,000
You think I'm crazy?

304
00:18:08,080 --> 00:18:09,640
Ah, okay, okay.

305
00:18:10,280 --> 00:18:12,520
-Hey, will you come home this afternoon? -No.

306
00:18:14,040 --> 00:18:15,480
I have chosen Albert.

307
00:18:17,080 --> 00:18:19,200
But who do you want to be with?

308
00:18:19,320 --> 00:18:21,960
Please, enough. I feel guilty already.

309
00:18:22,400 --> 00:18:27,160
Guilt, guilt, guilt, guilt. Forget the Jude-Christian guilt.

310
00:18:27,240 --> 00:18:28,760
Did you have a good time?

311
00:18:30,120 --> 00:18:31,440
Yes or no?

312
00:18:32,040 --> 00:18:33,040
Yes.

313
00:18:33,120 --> 00:18:36,120
So did I. Do you want to meet?

314
00:18:41,440 --> 00:18:42,720
At your place.

315
00:19:00,800 --> 00:19:01,960
Leave me alone! You are hurting me!

316
00:19:02,400 --> 00:19:04,400
-So? -I still didn't get my period.

317
00:19:04,920 --> 00:19:07,560
How can you be so calm? I didn't sleep all night!

318
00:19:07,960 --> 00:19:09,960
I try thinking about other things. Do you think I like it?

319
00:19:10,480 --> 00:19:12,480
-I'm nervous, too! -Take the test!

320
00:19:12,760 --> 00:19:14,720
I can't wait any longer, Berta. I'm freaking out!

321
00:19:15,240 --> 00:19:18,280
Let's go to the hospital or wherever you want, but now!

322
00:19:18,400 --> 00:19:19,520
I'm scared.

323
00:19:20,200 --> 00:19:22,920
Scared? The sooner we know, the better!

324
00:19:23,000 --> 00:19:24,360
No!

325
00:19:34,520 --> 00:19:36,520
-Who has material for the poem? -Me!

326
00:19:37,040 --> 00:19:39,240
All right. Go ahead. Quiet, you all.

327
00:19:39,320 --> 00:19:40,600
Okay. These are just two verses.

328
00:19:41,240 --> 00:19:45,520
"Like a wild horse, I gallop looking for your image."

329
00:19:46,760 --> 00:19:49,240
What? What are you laughing at? Do it yourselves!

330
00:19:49,320 --> 00:19:50,320
It's very good.

331
00:19:50,400 --> 00:19:53,920
No, no, no. I really like the horse idea. It's a powerful animal.

332
00:19:54,000 --> 00:19:56,680
We could use the Trojan horse story. Do you know it?

333
00:19:56,840 --> 00:19:58,880
-Yeah! -We studied it in Literature.

334
00:19:58,960 --> 00:20:00,400
Warriors hid inside a wooden horse

335
00:20:00,480 --> 00:20:02,480
to be able to cross the walls of a city.

336
00:20:02,560 --> 00:20:05,000
Well, we can use that story to make an allegory.

337
00:20:05,080 --> 00:20:08,360
The horse is a man. The walled city, a woman.

338
00:20:08,600 --> 00:20:10,900
Of course! The horse, I mean,

339
00:20:10,900 --> 00:20:13,840
the man wants to penetrate the woman.

340
00:20:18,120 --> 00:20:21,280
What is it, Vilaseca? Can't girls talk about penetration?

341
00:20:22,160 --> 00:20:24,040
-Of course! -Move on, move on.

342
00:20:24,120 --> 00:20:26,440
The wall is what the horse has to cross,

343
00:20:26,520 --> 00:20:29,400
the challenge which the lover aspires. Come on. More ideas.

344
00:20:31,080 --> 00:20:32,120
Gerard.

345
00:20:33,320 --> 00:20:36,640
We can use the horse, but the horse is...

346
00:20:36,720 --> 00:20:41,000
in front of the city, which represents the woman.

347
00:20:42,120 --> 00:20:44,720
-It doesn't matter, I got confused. -No, no. It's okay.

348
00:20:44,800 --> 00:20:46,320
You mean we should mention the horse and the city

349
00:20:46,400 --> 00:20:49,000
to introduce the poem's characters. Right?

350
00:20:50,120 --> 00:20:51,120
Yep.

351
00:20:51,200 --> 00:20:52,920
That's fine. It might be like,

352
00:20:55,440 --> 00:20:59,320
-"Like a wild horse..." -"At the gates of the city."

353
00:20:59,400 --> 00:21:02,000
Well done, Tania. "At the gates of the city."

354
00:21:05,040 --> 00:21:06,760
"I seek your image..."

355
00:21:06,880 --> 00:21:08,400
I'm getting a boner!

356
00:21:10,360 --> 00:21:12,160
Let's see. A word that rhymes with "City."

357
00:21:12,720 --> 00:21:14,040
Bitchy.

358
00:21:17,880 --> 00:21:21,320
I think it's cooler with "I'm a wild horse,"

359
00:21:21,400 --> 00:21:24,440
instead of "Like a wild horse." It sounds better.

360
00:21:24,880 --> 00:21:27,320
"I'm a wild horse..."

361
00:21:27,960 --> 00:21:30,400
Let's think. A word that rhymes with "City."

362
00:21:30,800 --> 00:21:33,280
I've got it! A beauty.

363
00:21:33,880 --> 00:21:37,280
The woman is a beauty. And it rhymes with "City."

364
00:21:37,720 --> 00:21:39,480
-Dammit, girl! You're good! -Yeah.

365
00:21:39,560 --> 00:21:42,080
Very well. "It's a beauty."

366
00:21:42,160 --> 00:21:43,440
You! Don't be an idiot!

367
00:21:43,640 --> 00:21:45,640
Hey! Joan has a poem and he doesn't want to read it!

368
00:21:45,720 --> 00:21:47,920
-Shut up, girl! -Come on!

369
00:21:48,000 --> 00:21:50,000
Leave him alone, if he doesn't want to read it!

370
00:21:50,560 --> 00:21:51,560
Come on!

371
00:21:51,640 --> 00:21:53,320
Come on! Read it!

372
00:21:53,480 --> 00:21:55,020
-Come on, Joan. Come on. No fear!

373
00:21:55,020 --> 00:21:56,800
-I've done it fast. You won't like it.

374
00:21:56,880 --> 00:21:58,960
You're a machine! You always get A's!

375
00:21:59,320 --> 00:22:00,320
Man! Read it!

376
00:22:00,400 --> 00:22:01,400
Come on, Joan.

377
00:22:01,480 --> 00:22:02,480
But it's that... I don't know.

378
00:22:02,560 --> 00:22:05,160
Come on, Joan. Read it. Otherwise, you'll regret it. Come on.

379
00:22:05,520 --> 00:22:06,600
Come on.

380
00:22:10,320 --> 00:22:13,720
"Even though your eyes can't see me..."

381
00:22:14,920 --> 00:22:16,760
The next one to laugh will leave the room.

382
00:22:22,680 --> 00:22:24,960
"Even though your eyes can't see me,

383
00:22:25,520 --> 00:22:28,280
I'm already part of you, like water from the Earth.

384
00:22:29,120 --> 00:22:32,240
I envy the wind that touches your whole skin."

385
00:22:36,440 --> 00:22:37,680
What a master!

386
00:22:37,760 --> 00:22:39,280
Man! Sign me an autograph!

387
00:22:39,560 --> 00:22:40,560
Well done, man!

388
00:22:40,640 --> 00:22:41,880
Sign me an autograph, right now!

389
00:22:42,360 --> 00:22:43,920
Well done, I'll take it.

390
00:22:44,440 --> 00:22:46,440
Who else has written verses at home?

391
00:22:47,640 --> 00:22:48,880
Bruno.

392
00:22:57,640 --> 00:22:59,080
"When you touch your cock,

393
00:23:00,160 --> 00:23:01,880
that means you haven't fucked in a while."

394
00:23:05,480 --> 00:23:08,280
No, that doesn't work. That's not erotic. It's porn.

395
00:23:09,640 --> 00:23:11,360
Bruno, you will sign the poem.

396
00:23:12,320 --> 00:23:15,160
And, if we win, you will go and collect the prize.

397
00:23:25,600 --> 00:23:28,000
Shit! Man, my mother has made a ham sandwich again.

398
00:23:28,320 --> 00:23:31,080
-So what? Make it yourself! -She makes it, I don't ask her!

399
00:23:32,400 --> 00:23:34,280
Bruno went overboard with the porn verse!

400
00:23:34,480 --> 00:23:36,480
I freaked out! Sometimes he is out of line with Santi, too.

401
00:23:36,560 --> 00:23:38,200
He will have problems at home today.

402
00:23:38,480 --> 00:23:39,840
The teacher is his father, so...

403
00:23:41,440 --> 00:23:43,480
Man, what's wrong?

404
00:23:44,440 --> 00:23:45,480
Nothing.

405
00:23:45,920 --> 00:23:47,160
You have broken up with Berta, haven't you?

406
00:23:47,320 --> 00:23:48,720
I told you not to! She's very hot!

407
00:23:48,800 --> 00:23:52,040
-Just fucking shut up! -Marc, leave him alone. I know what it is.

408
00:23:53,200 --> 00:23:54,480
What are you saying?

409
00:23:54,760 --> 00:23:56,680
I know what happens with Berta.

410
00:23:58,080 --> 00:23:59,240
Who told you that? Tania?

411
00:23:59,320 --> 00:24:01,400
Keep calm! We'll help you changing diapers.

412
00:24:04,080 --> 00:24:04,730
-What are you doing? You,

413
00:24:04,730 --> 00:24:05,840
bastard! -What's the matter with you, man?

414
00:24:05,920 --> 00:24:08,680
-Stop, stop, stop! -It was a joke, dammit!

415
00:24:09,760 --> 00:24:11,720
What are you doing? Come on! Man, what's going on?

416
00:24:12,080 --> 00:24:13,320
How old are you?

417
00:24:29,520 --> 00:24:31,240
You're lucky you've got only one day of detention.

418
00:24:33,440 --> 00:24:34,800
Blood tastes bad.

419
00:24:36,880 --> 00:24:39,040
I was going to tell Pol. I made a joke and...

420
00:24:41,080 --> 00:24:42,480
He's hysterical.

421
00:24:42,680 --> 00:24:45,680
Yeah. I'm not telling him anymore. He is a son of a bitch.

422
00:24:47,360 --> 00:24:48,520
I hate him.

423
00:24:48,600 --> 00:24:51,600
You don't hate him, Bruno. You've been friends for years.

424
00:24:51,880 --> 00:24:54,920
I was going to tell him that Berta is lying to him.

425
00:24:57,400 --> 00:24:59,720
I'm an idiot. I feel sorry for an asshole.

426
00:25:01,480 --> 00:25:04,040
Sorry? Nothing else?

427
00:25:07,520 --> 00:25:09,440
Why don't you tell me who you are in love with?

428
00:25:13,040 --> 00:25:14,160
Pol.

429
00:25:19,280 --> 00:25:22,200
-Doesn't your father know you're gay? -No way!

430
00:25:25,200 --> 00:25:27,800
-I suck, don't I? -No, you don't suck.

431
00:25:30,840 --> 00:25:31,920
A bit.

432
00:25:42,360 --> 00:25:44,160
In middle school, I always got in trouble.

433
00:25:44,640 --> 00:25:46,920
And it's been some time this hasn't happened.

434
00:25:48,000 --> 00:25:49,040
I'm like...

435
00:25:49,920 --> 00:25:51,360
I don't know. I lost control.

436
00:25:52,560 --> 00:25:54,560
I don't know what the hell is happening between you and Bruno.

437
00:25:55,480 --> 00:25:57,960
You, mysteriously silent throughout the class.

438
00:25:58,360 --> 00:26:00,520
And he bombards me with pornographic verses.

439
00:26:00,600 --> 00:26:03,800
And he says I get myself noticed! Now this argument.

440
00:26:04,040 --> 00:26:06,160
What happened? Bruno never gets into fights.

441
00:26:06,240 --> 00:26:09,200
-I lost control, dammit! -You should control your impulsiveness.

442
00:26:10,760 --> 00:26:12,800
-You are right. I was out of line.

443
00:26:12,800 --> 00:26:14,720
-You don't have to say it to me.

444
00:26:15,400 --> 00:26:16,880
I'll talk to Bruno.

445
00:26:20,120 --> 00:26:23,320
So, is this the room you are sent to, when you are in detention?

446
00:26:24,920 --> 00:26:27,480
Great. I've just chosen this place...

447
00:26:27,720 --> 00:26:31,040
to receive students who have questions about the subject.

448
00:26:31,520 --> 00:26:32,920
No teacher has a private office,

449
00:26:33,000 --> 00:26:34,560
and there are more teachers overseeing detention.

450
00:26:34,960 --> 00:26:35,870
Just because it's always

451
00:26:35,880 --> 00:26:37,680
been that way doesn't mean it can't be changed.

452
00:26:39,800 --> 00:26:41,270
-I'll talk to Bruno this afternoon.

453
00:26:41,270 --> 00:26:43,000
-He won't be at home. He has dance class.

454
00:26:43,480 --> 00:26:44,680
What?

455
00:26:45,640 --> 00:26:46,920
Bruno dances?

456
00:26:47,120 --> 00:26:48,880
Yes. Shit. I shouldn't have mentioned.

457
00:26:49,040 --> 00:26:50,400
Yes, yes. He dances.

458
00:26:51,200 --> 00:26:54,560
He likes dancing. But do me a favor and don't tell anyone.

459
00:26:54,640 --> 00:26:55,800
He doesn't want anyone to know.

460
00:26:56,040 --> 00:26:58,360
Things of your idiotic age.

461
00:26:59,240 --> 00:27:00,320
Okay, okay.

462
00:27:01,160 --> 00:27:06,040
-Go and apologize. -Have you ever apologized?

463
00:27:06,200 --> 00:27:07,640
Bye, Pol.

464
00:27:14,440 --> 00:27:17,080
That's it. The kid laughed at me.

465
00:27:17,440 --> 00:27:18,920
And I got mad at him.

466
00:27:19,600 --> 00:27:21,560
Those junior students have changed.

467
00:27:21,640 --> 00:27:23,120
Yes, I know that.

468
00:27:23,480 --> 00:27:27,400
They are very rude. You know, authority and patience.

469
00:27:28,240 --> 00:27:29,600
What else?

470
00:27:29,720 --> 00:27:30,840
-Hi. -Hey.

471
00:27:35,080 --> 00:27:38,920
-Eugeni, I want to talk to you. -I don't have time.

472
00:27:40,800 --> 00:27:43,160
I realize that what I have done with Iván wasn't nice.

473
00:27:44,560 --> 00:27:46,400
I shouldn't have done it without your consent.

474
00:27:48,040 --> 00:27:49,320
Excuse me?

475
00:27:50,400 --> 00:27:53,840
Fuck. What else do you want? I'm apologizing.

476
00:27:55,080 --> 00:27:58,800
Apology accepted. Good luck in detention.

477
00:28:02,160 --> 00:28:04,640
-Toni, I want to talk to you. -Yes. Tell me.

478
00:28:05,400 --> 00:28:07,280
The Philosophy's syllabus is very dense.

479
00:28:07,760 --> 00:28:09,920
Students have difficulty to understand some concepts.

480
00:28:10,000 --> 00:28:14,080
I could provide tutoring for those who want to ask me about it.

481
00:28:14,800 --> 00:28:16,160
Could I use the detention room,

482
00:28:16,160 --> 00:28:17,880
since I'm spending so many hours there?

483
00:28:20,560 --> 00:28:21,760
Now I understand.

484
00:28:21,840 --> 00:28:24,960
That's why you apologized to Eugeni in front of me, right?

485
00:28:25,160 --> 00:28:28,160
-So you could ask for this privilege. -No, Toni. No.

486
00:28:28,240 --> 00:28:29,920
That's not my style. No.

487
00:28:30,080 --> 00:28:33,880
I just ask for a room for students in need...

488
00:28:33,960 --> 00:28:35,160
after class.

489
00:28:35,280 --> 00:28:37,160
You can talk to them in the Department of Language.

490
00:28:37,280 --> 00:28:38,800
But there are other teachers there.

491
00:28:38,880 --> 00:28:41,440
No teacher can have tutoring hours

492
00:28:41,520 --> 00:28:42,600
in a private room.

493
00:28:42,680 --> 00:28:45,480
Most parents can not explain these concepts.

494
00:28:45,960 --> 00:28:47,360
It's a practical issue.

495
00:28:47,440 --> 00:28:48,880
Toni, I think the PTA would appreciate it.

496
00:28:48,960 --> 00:28:51,360
Don't tell me you're doing that to please the PTA, Merli.

497
00:28:51,600 --> 00:28:54,160
You do it for you. You showed me yours cards on day one.

498
00:28:54,280 --> 00:28:56,640
What you want is to be alone

499
00:28:56,720 --> 00:28:59,400
in a place away from other teachers.

500
00:28:59,520 --> 00:29:03,240
Yes, I admit. I'm very independent.

501
00:29:03,320 --> 00:29:05,600
And I get along with students a thousand times better.

502
00:29:06,240 --> 00:29:10,040
Listen. I only ask for about six hours, throughout the week.

503
00:29:10,720 --> 00:29:13,840
I can do it while I'm taking care of detention. Or chaperoning.

504
00:29:13,920 --> 00:29:16,880
I think it could go well for me and for them, too.

505
00:29:20,520 --> 00:29:24,040
Six hours during school hours, if the room is not occupied.

506
00:29:24,600 --> 00:29:26,800
-Very good. -You've convinced me. See?

507
00:29:27,600 --> 00:29:28,920
You told me the truth.

508
00:29:29,760 --> 00:29:32,160
Spare me your manipulations, please.

509
00:29:36,520 --> 00:29:40,920
One, two, three. Raise your chin, Bruno.

510
00:29:41,760 --> 00:29:46,160
Five, six, seven. And right foot.

511
00:29:46,720 --> 00:29:47,960
Start again.

512
00:29:48,280 --> 00:29:51,000
One, two, three, four,

513
00:29:51,680 --> 00:29:55,760
five, six, seven.

514
00:29:56,400 --> 00:29:57,480
We stand.

515
00:29:59,240 --> 00:30:00,240
And right foot.

516
00:30:00,840 --> 00:30:03,840
Perfect. Let's stop here. We continue tomorrow.

517
00:30:27,600 --> 00:30:28,840
You kept pretty quiet about this.

518
00:30:30,680 --> 00:30:32,320
Did my father tell you I was here?

519
00:30:33,240 --> 00:30:34,600
He let it slip.

520
00:30:38,080 --> 00:30:39,520
What do you want, Pol?

521
00:30:40,320 --> 00:30:41,480
Does it hurt?

522
00:30:44,320 --> 00:30:45,520
Man, I know...

523
00:30:45,920 --> 00:30:48,200
I'm very nervous, you know why.

524
00:30:48,960 --> 00:30:50,920
If Berta is pregnant, I'll die.

525
00:30:52,320 --> 00:30:53,680
Aren't you in love with Berta anymore?

526
00:30:54,960 --> 00:30:56,480
No, I never fall in love.

527
00:30:57,040 --> 00:30:58,120
I'm like this.

528
00:31:00,720 --> 00:31:02,160
What a shitty day!

529
00:31:05,880 --> 00:31:07,280
See you at school, okay?

530
00:31:10,240 --> 00:31:11,560
Pol! Wait!

531
00:31:16,440 --> 00:31:18,200
Berta is not pregnant.

532
00:31:19,280 --> 00:31:21,600
She made it up because you wanted to break up.

533
00:31:24,160 --> 00:31:25,720
Really?

534
00:31:27,720 --> 00:31:31,240
Dammit! I can't believe it! What a bitch!

535
00:31:42,120 --> 00:31:43,200
I'll see you in class!

536
00:31:44,000 --> 00:31:45,000
Bruno!

537
00:31:46,080 --> 00:31:49,280
You dance fucking great! Yes.

538
00:32:01,600 --> 00:32:08,000
How did pol know you have dance class?

539
00:32:08,080 --> 00:32:09,120
Guess

540
00:32:09,200 --> 00:32:11,040
Merli?

541
00:32:11,120 --> 00:32:12,640
FUCKING Merli!

542
00:32:24,720 --> 00:32:25,720
Damn shit!

543
00:32:25,800 --> 00:32:27,280
Didn't you tell me he wouldn't be here?

544
00:32:27,640 --> 00:32:28,960
Give it to me!

545
00:32:29,320 --> 00:32:30,720
This can't be happening to me!

546
00:32:30,800 --> 00:32:32,520
Why are you back from dance so soon, son?

547
00:32:32,600 --> 00:32:34,680
No! Not son! I want a DNA test!

548
00:32:35,280 --> 00:32:37,040
You inherited your grandmother's genes.

549
00:32:37,120 --> 00:32:38,880
Join the theater. You will succeed.

550
00:32:38,960 --> 00:32:40,080
Dad, shut up!

551
00:32:43,880 --> 00:32:45,520
If Albert finds out...

552
00:32:58,640 --> 00:33:00,520
Were you practicing for your erotic poem?

553
00:33:00,640 --> 00:33:01,640
Do you want some fuet?

554
00:33:01,720 --> 00:33:02,960
Do you realize what you've done, dad?

555
00:33:03,280 --> 00:33:04,520
Dammit! What time is it?

556
00:33:04,680 --> 00:33:06,240
Iván Blasco is waiting for me.

557
00:33:08,040 --> 00:33:09,400
You do as if nothing happened.

558
00:33:09,600 --> 00:33:12,280
In fact, nothing happens if I'm late. He'll be there, for sure.

559
00:33:12,600 --> 00:33:15,400
Dad! Laia has a boyfriend! The PE teacher!

560
00:33:16,400 --> 00:33:18,000
Laia came voluntarily.

561
00:33:18,080 --> 00:33:20,240
If she cheats on the guy, it's not my problem.

562
00:33:20,680 --> 00:33:22,080
-No, no! Don't dramatize! -I don't dramatize!

563
00:33:22,160 --> 00:33:23,840
And get dressed, dammit! You're naked!

564
00:33:23,920 --> 00:33:25,320
Okay! Calm down!

565
00:33:36,240 --> 00:33:38,720
Luckily you are here! I'm so nervous.

566
00:33:39,040 --> 00:33:40,600
-Do you know anything yet? -No.

567
00:33:41,480 --> 00:33:43,240
-I talked to my dad, I told him.

568
00:33:43,240 --> 00:33:45,120
-What did you tell him, you idiot?

569
00:33:45,760 --> 00:33:47,920
-That we might have a child. -What?

570
00:33:48,400 --> 00:33:49,930
He will help us. Now let's go to your home,

571
00:33:49,930 --> 00:33:50,720
talk to your mother...

572
00:33:50,800 --> 00:33:52,360
No, no! I don't want to talk to anyone!

573
00:33:52,960 --> 00:33:54,640
Why not?

574
00:33:55,640 --> 00:33:57,120
Because I'm not pregnant.

575
00:33:58,520 --> 00:34:00,400
I know you're not, bitch!

576
00:34:01,120 --> 00:34:02,880
Bruno told me you made it up!

577
00:34:03,880 --> 00:34:05,680
-I'd like to be... -No! Don't touch me, Berta!

578
00:34:05,840 --> 00:34:07,200
Don't touch me!

579
00:34:07,640 --> 00:34:09,890
Do you know the dirty trick you've pulled on me?

580
00:34:09,890 --> 00:34:11,160
Do you know how bad I felt?

581
00:34:12,840 --> 00:34:14,840
Isn't deceiving me with false feelings a bastard's trick?

582
00:34:15,240 --> 00:34:17,200
Making me believe you loved me just to fuck?

583
00:34:17,320 --> 00:34:18,840
I know! But you can't compare!

584
00:34:19,320 --> 00:34:21,120
Dammit! Making me believe that you're pregnant?

585
00:34:21,840 --> 00:34:23,040
-You're not right in the head!

586
00:34:23,040 --> 00:34:24,560
-The guys think you're a fucking hero,

587
00:34:24,720 --> 00:34:27,520
but the girls think you are a cocky moron and a hypocrite!

588
00:34:29,280 --> 00:34:30,520
But I love you.

589
00:34:31,760 --> 00:34:33,040
I don't want to be with you anymore.

590
00:34:33,680 --> 00:34:35,120
Especially after what you've done.

591
00:34:36,040 --> 00:34:38,640
You've screwed me and I've screwed you. We are even.

592
00:34:51,680 --> 00:34:54,480
Can't you keep a secret or what?

593
00:34:55,720 --> 00:35:00,960
Sorry, you're right I told bruno

594
00:35:01,040 --> 00:35:04,120
You're a bitch

595
00:35:04,200 --> 00:35:09,720
I didn't know he would tell pol I'm sorry

596
00:35:10,400 --> 00:35:12,160
Don't talk to me

597
00:35:13,400 --> 00:35:14,560
Fuck.

598
00:35:17,000 --> 00:35:19,560
Since today is our first day of class,

599
00:35:20,000 --> 00:35:22,440
we start with the most important subject.

600
00:35:23,560 --> 00:35:24,720
Philosophy.

601
00:35:25,640 --> 00:35:26,960
Today, Plato.

602
00:35:28,240 --> 00:35:29,880
I'm going to tell you a story.

603
00:35:30,280 --> 00:35:31,680
The myth of the cave.

604
00:35:32,600 --> 00:35:33,600
Turn off the light.

605
00:35:39,800 --> 00:35:41,800
Sit down.

606
00:35:41,880 --> 00:35:43,200
Hey, this room is nasty. Next time, I want it cleaned.

607
00:35:43,880 --> 00:35:45,520
Deal? Sit down.

608
00:35:48,040 --> 00:35:49,320
Look, this is a cave.

609
00:35:51,040 --> 00:35:54,360
Inside the cave, there are some men

610
00:35:54,840 --> 00:35:58,360
who've been chained for a long time by their feet and neck.

611
00:35:59,320 --> 00:36:01,040
They can only look forward.

612
00:36:03,440 --> 00:36:05,200
Behind them there's a wall.

613
00:36:06,040 --> 00:36:08,200
And behind the wall, a fire.

614
00:36:10,160 --> 00:36:11,720
The men who maintain the fire

615
00:36:12,440 --> 00:36:15,360
move figures over the wall,

616
00:36:18,000 --> 00:36:20,960
that are projected on the wall of the cave.

617
00:36:24,400 --> 00:36:25,480
You see?

618
00:36:29,800 --> 00:36:34,360
The prisoners think the reflected shadows are the reality,

619
00:36:35,360 --> 00:36:38,720
because that's the only thing they can see. Are you following?

620
00:36:42,120 --> 00:36:47,080
One of the men manages to get free from the chains

621
00:36:48,640 --> 00:36:50,480
and comes out of the cave.

622
00:36:53,200 --> 00:36:54,880
The sun blinds him,

623
00:36:56,120 --> 00:36:58,120
but little by little he gets used to the light

624
00:37:00,080 --> 00:37:03,760
and discovers that reality is what's outside.

625
00:37:05,640 --> 00:37:07,880
Not the shadows in the cave.

626
00:37:13,080 --> 00:37:14,200
Iván, look at me.

627
00:37:16,240 --> 00:37:17,560
Look at me.

628
00:37:21,080 --> 00:37:22,840
I'll get you out of the cave.

629
00:37:33,600 --> 00:37:36,880
One week later

630
00:37:37,360 --> 00:37:39,760
Santi, take junior and senior students to the hall.

631
00:37:40,560 --> 00:37:41,920
And you, Merli, the freshmen.

632
00:37:42,000 --> 00:37:44,280
And hang this next to Reception, please.

633
00:37:59,160 --> 00:37:59,960
Yes?

634
00:38:00,040 --> 00:38:02,680
-Excuse me. Are you the janitor? -Do I look like a janitor?

635
00:38:03,200 --> 00:38:05,040
-No. I don't know. -How may I help?

636
00:38:05,200 --> 00:38:07,000
I have to give these keys to my son.

637
00:38:07,280 --> 00:38:08,520
Do you want me to give them to him?

638
00:38:08,680 --> 00:38:10,320
You don't have to be so formal.

639
00:38:10,520 --> 00:38:13,160
And you don't have to be so informal. Why should you?

640
00:38:13,560 --> 00:38:15,160
Look, I have no time to waste.

641
00:38:21,200 --> 00:38:23,840
When you get at his home, there is an ice-cream shop, you go down

642
00:38:23,920 --> 00:38:25,480
and it's as if...

643
00:38:28,760 --> 00:38:29,760
What a fool!

644
00:38:29,840 --> 00:38:31,560
Come on! Up! Are you all right?

645
00:38:31,640 --> 00:38:32,920
I'm fine, I'm not hurt. It was the music. I'm all right.

646
00:38:33,000 --> 00:38:34,080
Sure?

647
00:38:34,160 --> 00:38:35,520
Yeah! Leave me alone!

648
00:38:38,680 --> 00:38:39,840
Berta!

649
00:38:42,080 --> 00:38:43,600
Are you still mad at me?

650
00:38:47,960 --> 00:38:49,720
Girl! You've been weird for a week!

651
00:38:50,120 --> 00:38:52,800
I did apologize. I never thought Bruno would tell Pol.

652
00:38:54,240 --> 00:38:55,600
You should have thought better.

653
00:38:55,720 --> 00:38:57,720
Now what? Will we be this way the entire school year?

654
00:39:02,880 --> 00:39:06,000
What if we go to the cafeteria? I'm inviting. So?

655
00:39:10,040 --> 00:39:12,760
You're right. It's not my plan to be this way this whole year.

656
00:39:13,880 --> 00:39:15,560
But be careful about what you tell!

657
00:39:21,920 --> 00:39:24,320
Kids! All to the theater!

658
00:39:24,400 --> 00:39:26,560
The awards ceremony is starting!

659
00:39:27,400 --> 00:39:29,600
Come on! We'll win!

660
00:39:30,240 --> 00:39:31,240
-Great. -If we win, you'll see.

661
00:39:40,480 --> 00:39:44,080
-Have you prepared a speech? -No. What do you want me to say?

662
00:39:44,480 --> 00:39:45,480
You could dance!

663
00:39:45,920 --> 00:39:48,920
Very well. Now we turn to the category "Poetry."

664
00:39:50,240 --> 00:39:51,240
Let's see.

665
00:39:51,880 --> 00:39:53,920
The third prize was not awarded.

666
00:39:56,000 --> 00:39:58,080
Yes. But the second prize has a winner.

667
00:39:58,880 --> 00:40:00,430
The jury has decided to

668
00:40:00,430 --> 00:40:03,280
award the prize to the poem "Erotic Troy."

669
00:40:03,440 --> 00:40:04,880
Great!

670
00:40:07,200 --> 00:40:10,800
This poem was signed with a pseudonym.

671
00:40:11,560 --> 00:40:15,480
"Peripatetic." And his author collects the prize. Bruno Bergeron.

672
00:40:16,000 --> 00:40:17,000
Yes!

673
00:40:23,000 --> 00:40:25,280
Bravo! Pretty good!

674
00:40:32,520 --> 00:40:36,680
Hi. I'd like to dedicate this prize to my classmates...

675
00:40:36,920 --> 00:40:38,240
Yes, sir!

676
00:40:40,480 --> 00:40:41,950
and... I want to say that

677
00:40:41,950 --> 00:40:44,560
it wouldn't have been possible without them.

678
00:40:46,240 --> 00:40:47,240
That's it.

679
00:40:47,320 --> 00:40:48,510
Wait a minute! Wait a minute,

680
00:40:48,510 --> 00:40:50,120
Bruno! Wait. I'd like to say something.

681
00:40:50,600 --> 00:40:52,360
I want to say something, if you excuse me.

682
00:40:55,240 --> 00:40:56,600
He wouldn't dare say it's ours.

683
00:40:57,160 --> 00:40:58,560
This guy is crazy!

684
00:41:00,080 --> 00:41:03,040
Let's see. I just want to say

685
00:41:03,240 --> 00:41:06,800
that this poem wasn't written only by Bruno.

686
00:41:08,520 --> 00:41:12,720
It was written by all students in the Peripatetics' class,

687
00:41:12,960 --> 00:41:14,560
who accepted my proposal.

688
00:41:15,440 --> 00:41:16,520
What the fuck!

689
00:41:16,600 --> 00:41:18,080
And we learned two things:

690
00:41:18,680 --> 00:41:21,480
to work in group and how pleasing it is to write.

691
00:41:21,680 --> 00:41:24,080
And I want to congratulate them, because they kept a secret.

692
00:41:26,040 --> 00:41:27,400
Yes!

693
00:41:47,480 --> 00:41:50,560
Just 15 days and you broke the rules again.

694
00:41:50,640 --> 00:41:51,950
Toni, please. They have

695
00:41:51,950 --> 00:41:54,520
learned to do something together. I told you.

696
00:41:54,600 --> 00:41:56,760
You talk about working together.

697
00:41:56,840 --> 00:41:58,800
What about you? You're not a team player.

698
00:41:58,880 --> 00:42:01,600
-I only think about my students. -The peripatetics.

699
00:42:01,680 --> 00:42:04,760
Don't tell me how to teach. Philosophy is my turf.

700
00:42:04,840 --> 00:42:06,760
Philosophy, yes. Not poetry.

701
00:42:06,840 --> 00:42:09,560
They've based the poem on Plato's idea of love.

702
00:42:10,040 --> 00:42:12,560
Just ask them and see. They know it by heart.

703
00:42:12,640 --> 00:42:15,680
We could give them a test today and they would get only A's.

704
00:42:15,880 --> 00:42:16,940
Yes, great. I like that

705
00:42:16,940 --> 00:42:18,880
they are learning with a different method.

706
00:42:18,960 --> 00:42:21,000
But you are revolutionizing the chicken-coop.

707
00:42:21,120 --> 00:42:23,240
It was all very calm until you came along.

708
00:42:23,360 --> 00:42:25,150
So calm that only ten students

709
00:42:25,150 --> 00:42:27,600
entered the literary contest, out of 300.

710
00:42:27,880 --> 00:42:28,880
And do you know why?

711
00:42:29,320 --> 00:42:31,400
Because they believe they can't write.

712
00:42:31,560 --> 00:42:33,400
Because nobody has encouraged them.

713
00:42:33,640 --> 00:42:36,920
What's the harm if the whole class enters the contest?

714
00:42:37,840 --> 00:42:39,000
Tell that to Bruno.

715
00:42:39,960 --> 00:42:42,200
After having embarrassed him in front of everybody.

716
00:42:43,040 --> 00:42:44,800
You could have spared him.

717
00:42:46,200 --> 00:42:49,080
When you cheat, you can't tell. Or it's no longer cheating.

718
00:42:49,480 --> 00:42:50,680
Did you have to tell the truth?

719
00:42:51,360 --> 00:42:52,760
Listen, Merli.

720
00:42:52,960 --> 00:42:55,240
I know you can motivate students better than anyone,

721
00:42:55,320 --> 00:42:57,040
and that's why I like having you here.

722
00:42:57,280 --> 00:42:58,520
But I don't want trouble.

723
00:42:58,880 --> 00:43:01,520
Try making your talent more discreet, dammit.

724
00:43:04,400 --> 00:43:07,280
Now, get out. There is a queue of teachers who want to complain

725
00:43:07,360 --> 00:43:08,960
and I'm supposed to save your ass.

726
00:43:11,720 --> 00:43:13,080
Come on, Toni! Throw it!

727
00:43:16,960 --> 00:43:19,000
It seems you have butterfingers, kid!

728
00:43:21,640 --> 00:43:24,080
-Hi. -Hi, Bruno. You all right?

729
00:43:24,800 --> 00:43:29,760
Yes. My father has messed it up again, as always. It's his style.

730
00:43:30,880 --> 00:43:32,000
I like him.

731
00:43:32,760 --> 00:43:33,760
Really?

732
00:43:34,240 --> 00:43:36,240
Come on! Throw it! He's an intriguing guy.

733
00:43:37,000 --> 00:43:38,680
Very, very intriguing.

734
00:43:40,200 --> 00:43:42,400
Do you want me to tell you some of his intrigues?

735
00:43:44,720 --> 00:43:46,120
Everyone is talking about you.

736
00:43:46,560 --> 00:43:48,880
And I feel bad when someone talks about you.

737
00:43:48,960 --> 00:43:51,840
You feel bad because you feel guilty.

738
00:43:52,120 --> 00:43:54,320
You shouldn't take it so seriously, Laia.

739
00:43:54,520 --> 00:43:56,400
What's happened to us is fantastic!

740
00:43:56,480 --> 00:43:58,520
Besides, we haven't met for days.

741
00:43:59,840 --> 00:44:00,960
What are you doing?

742
00:44:01,400 --> 00:44:03,470
You teach your students to keep secrets,

743
00:44:03,470 --> 00:44:04,920
but your son hasn't learned.

744
00:44:05,000 --> 00:44:07,560
-Albert! Alb...! -Don't touch me!

745
00:44:11,720 --> 00:44:12,800
Fuck.

746
00:44:22,400 --> 00:44:24,040
Then came the turkey. And he told everyone

747
00:44:24,320 --> 00:44:27,200
that we wrote that poem together and that he's proud of us.

748
00:44:27,680 --> 00:44:29,640
He did that? In front of everyone?

749
00:44:29,880 --> 00:44:32,640
Yes, yes. Gee! Bruno wanted to die on that stage.

750
00:44:33,000 --> 00:44:34,000
Poor him.

751
00:44:34,320 --> 00:44:36,440
He is unbelievable. Merli is unbelievable, really.

752
00:44:36,720 --> 00:44:38,040
I think he's brilliant.

753
00:44:38,640 --> 00:44:41,680
What teacher manages to encourage teenagers to write a poem?

754
00:44:42,680 --> 00:44:44,960
You guys think poetry is shit.

755
00:44:45,040 --> 00:44:48,200
-Yeah. Everything in rhymes. -I have to know Merli.

756
00:44:49,120 --> 00:44:51,360
No, mom. Don't come near the institute.

757
00:44:51,440 --> 00:44:53,160
If it's for a good reason, I want to congratulate him.

758
00:44:53,240 --> 00:44:56,200
I know. But no. I don't want you to go, okay?

759
00:44:56,280 --> 00:44:59,160
It's not okay. It's childish that mothers...

760
00:45:00,040 --> 00:45:02,120
-Shit. You will go, right? -Yes.

761
00:45:41,000 --> 00:45:42,560
-Hi. -Hi.

762
00:45:45,920 --> 00:45:47,080
Sit down.

763
00:45:58,040 --> 00:46:00,360
I crashed into a door.

764
00:46:01,800 --> 00:46:03,480
-Are you hurt? -Eh? No.

765
00:46:07,400 --> 00:46:10,640
-I think I'm going to bed. -No, wait, wait.

766
00:46:11,240 --> 00:46:12,640
Open this book.

767
00:46:23,680 --> 00:46:24,920
"The banquet"?

768
00:46:27,200 --> 00:46:31,760
In that book, Plato describes many forms of love.

769
00:47:02,840 --> 00:47:04,480
Out there is the world of the living.

770
00:47:04,880 --> 00:47:06,960
Don't forget that you are a part of it, too.

771
00:47:07,160 --> 00:47:11,280
How many lives do you think you have? Only one life!

772
00:47:11,560 --> 00:47:14,440
Pol Rubio, Bruno Bergeron.

773
00:47:14,520 --> 00:47:16,120
Thank you for participating.

774
00:47:16,360 --> 00:47:17,520
A fucking F.

775
00:47:17,600 --> 00:47:19,960
Do you learn that kind of impertinence at home?

776
00:47:20,720 --> 00:47:23,080
The best thing you can do is to study for the next test,

777
00:47:23,400 --> 00:47:24,840
which is in three days.

778
00:47:25,000 --> 00:47:26,280
-What? Three days? -How can you...

779
00:47:26,360 --> 00:47:28,720
-Eugeni has it in for me. -We have talked about this, right?

780
00:47:28,800 --> 00:47:30,440
He hates me because I'm your son.

781
00:47:30,560 --> 00:47:34,560
Well, we have a new student. Her name is Monica de Villamore.

782
00:47:35,400 --> 00:47:37,800
-Wipe the drool. -I think I'm falling in love.

783
00:47:38,000 --> 00:47:40,160
You admit that you unfairly failed him.

784
00:47:40,240 --> 00:47:43,160
No way. He failed, that's all.

785
00:47:43,800 --> 00:47:45,680
Tell little Bergeron

786
00:47:45,960 --> 00:47:48,320
to study hard for the test the day after tomorrow.

787
00:47:48,800 --> 00:47:51,880
You said if we have questions, then...

788
00:47:51,960 --> 00:47:55,680
Yes, questions about Philosophy, not on how to flirt.

789
00:47:55,760 --> 00:47:57,120
But you don't have any, I don't know,

790
00:47:57,200 --> 00:47:58,520
technique, or something like that?

791
00:47:58,720 --> 00:47:59,720
Technique?

792
00:47:59,800 --> 00:48:01,640
-You are going to study at your place? -So what?

793
00:48:01,720 --> 00:48:02,920
He is not like you.

794
00:48:03,280 --> 00:48:05,040
We're friends, right? That's it.

795
00:48:05,320 --> 00:48:06,920
How old were you when your mother died?

796
00:48:07,680 --> 00:48:08,960
Nine.

797
00:48:09,840 --> 00:48:11,520
Damn, so many questions, right?

798
00:48:12,680 --> 00:48:14,250
Gerard is delighted with your

799
00:48:14,250 --> 00:48:16,960
classes and I love to see him happy. I appreciate.

800
00:48:17,120 --> 00:48:18,240
I'm late for work.

801
00:48:19,440 --> 00:48:21,520
-Goodbye, Merli. -Goodbye.

