Mireia, this week you made many photocopies.
Sorry.
It's okay. I only say this for you to keep it in mind.
Today, those suspended will come back.
-They will soon have the Philosophy test. -Good.
Today, your savior is back.
My savior? What are you talking about?
You pretend not to understand.
What's wrong, Eugeni? You haven't taken your pill today?
You earn the kids' trust. Then they stand up for you.
It's logical to remember that you are quite popular.
No, you're more well-known. The students call you Hitler.
You have done a shitty test. A disaster.
No, my students,
you don't deserve to be called "Peripatetics."
Socrates
Berta, F.
Tania, you have a D. Pity.
Marc, C. Barely.
Come in.
-C? -Come in.
You three, remember you will take a test on Thursday.
Monica, B.
-Good. -Great.
Gerard, you deserve a D, but I put down a D plus.
-D? It is impossible. -Sit down.
Don't ever write down again that Aristotle is Plato's father.
-Man... -You said it.
No. I said he was his disciple, not his father.
You didn't fail for that. The concepts are not well explained.
Oh Lord!
The philosopher that I present
to you now is one of the greats. Socrates.
With this, you'll have a hard on.
-Good morning, Jaume. -Hey, what's up?
-Sit down. -Thank you.
You're welcome.
What's up? How is Joan?
He's repent. I still don't
understand why he decided to steal the test.
I wanted to talk to you and I want you to know that, to me,
Joan is still one of the best students we've had.
I won't consider that he took one copy of the test.
Thank you.
I hope this ends up as an anecdote.
I appreciate that you only suspended him for three days.
We, teachers, considered his academic record.
We decided the punishment for him and his friends.
Friends, friends. His friends are bad influence.
I don't think the bad influence is them, exactly.
It's not? Then who?
I don't know. At this age, they are all rebels.
It's harder for them to get used to changes.
What kind of change?
No, everything here is the same.
Just that there's a new Philosophy teacher. Merli.
Merli. Yes. Joan talks a lot about him.
He is Bruno's father, isn't he?
Yes. He teaches differently. He befriends the students.
He doesn't limit himself to be just a teacher.
And he is able to guide them to following his thinking.
-It's just an opinion. -I don't like it.
-This means he puts ideas in their heads. -The kids love it.
It makes the class enjoyable. He makes them think.
That's good, Jaume.
But I think the ethical issue needs discussion.
I hope he doesn't indoctrinate them.
Do you think that it's right for parents to make you think
what's best for you?
Do not let anyone impose their way of thinking on you!
You are old enough to think for yourselves.
Bruno, this applies to you, too.
Merli, when you say don't
let anyone impose their way of thinking on us,
you're imposing your thinking on us.
No, excuse me, I'm asking you to think for yourselves.
What if I don't want to think?
-Do I have to do that? -Then, no.
No, it's okay.
You're not obliged to think if you don't want to. It's okay.
-Okay. -Very good.
Socrates was sentenced to death,
accused of corrupting the young ones
and doubting their gods' existence.
When the only thing he did
was questioning the ideas they wanted to fill his head with.
More than 2,000 years ago,
that "Power" Tells us what we must do and think.
They want us submissive and silent. They can go to hell.
You did all of this? Have you learned how to cook?
My mother made them.
Today, I saw that you're very
attentive and interested in Socrates lesson.
Do you know that he had a chance to take back his words
to save himself from being sentenced to death?
He didn't do it.
He followed them to the end.
He drank a glass of hemlock poison.
That gesture made him go down in history.
What if your gesture is useless, Joan?
Is your sacrifice for me worth it?
It's just that, I didn't do it for you.
I did it for myself.
Very well.
And when Marc saw that I got a D,
he looked at me with a sad face.
I wanted to eat him.
I was thinking, "Come comfort me, man.
Come comfort me and we can freak out together."
I didn't know you liked Marc that much.
-No, I don't like him. -Really?
-It's okay if you don't want to talk. -I like him a bit.
-But don't say anything. -No, I won't.
-I like him since the beginning of course. -Really?
On the first day, I thought,
"I would fuck him."
Girl, if he likes you, then it would be easy.
-Because he comes on really strong. -He is?
I know he does.
But I think he has a super deep background.
-I like that he does drama. -Tania?
Tania, thank you, thank you.
-Thanks you for giving me the answer. -Chill.
If it weren't for you, I would have flunked Philosophy.
Whatever I can do for a friend.
-But you got a D. -I don't care.
Lucky that she helped you.
Yes. I owe you one, cutie.
-Bye. -Bye.
Girlfriend!
-What if he wants something? -I don't know.
-He hugged you. -It's true.
Yes, but he hugged me to thank,
not because he wants something else.
-Not with this hair. -Don't you like your hair?
-I know how to do haircut. -You do?
Yes, my aunt is a hairdresser. She taught me.
Come on. It's too boring at home.
-Take the chance. -Okay. Let's go.
But don't you overdo it.
-I don't want to scare him. -No. You will surprise him.
Okay.
He said he gave me a D plus, but I deserved a D.
As if he did you a favor. He got nerve.
You helped me study. How did he know?
I repeated the lesson a thousand times.
Eudaimonia. "The myth of the cave." I knew it pretty well.
Men chained in a cave.
Yes, you knew it well. You deserved at least a B plus.
He laughed at my test in front of everyone.
Just because I made a stupid mistake, I don't know what.
I can imagine what tone he used.
I don't know what you see in that teacher.
At first, friendly with the students.
When it's time to grade them, he forgets it.
-This time, he went overboard.
-If I could, I would tell you something.
-Calm down. I won't talk to him. -No, I will talk to him.
Because, if it were you, what would you say to him?
Gerard told me you humiliated him in front of the whole class.
Sorry. I have never humiliated any student.
You laughed at his test.
He wrote that Aristotle and
Plato were father and son. That was funny.
Okay, I admit that it was funny. But he doesn't deserve a D plus.
He deserves a D, but I scored him higher.
I asked him the questions the night before and he knew them all.
-Plato, Aristotle, the cave.
-He wasn't able to repeat it in the test.
I have never seen him study that much in his life.
He was aiming for the best mark. He was excited.
He deserves at least a B or a B plus.
Do you know what I think, Merli?
The grade has something to do with us.
With us? Sorry, did I miss something?
You understand me. Because Gina doesn't say what I want to hear,
I won't give a good mark to her son.
Don't tell me that's not true.
Are you telling me that the grade I give Gerard
depends on whether I can hook up with his mother?
Yes. It seems so.
You can calm down. Gerard will have a B plus.
So fast? No, no, no. I want you to check the test again...
No. I will check it, but I
tell you in advance that I will give him a B.
Now I have go to work.
Of course, even though I don't accept your interference,
you still turn me on.
-Tania. -What do you want?
-Hey, the other day, I was nervous. -So what?
-You said harsh things to me, too. -Now you're the victim?
-No, I don't play the victim, Tania. -No, no, bullshit.
Leave me alone.
Pol doesn't talk to me, neither do you. Am I really an asshole?
Look, today the fatso has a nice day.
I'd rather be with people who respect me.
Leave me alone, will you?
The beer is coming. Even though it was in the last minute.
Come in. Bye. There's food in the fridge.
If anything happens, call me. I'll come running.
Don't spend all day on the Internet. How is your cold?
-I'll turn up the heater. -What time do I give him the porridge?
What newspapers do you read on the Internet?
All of them.
Sport, too?
I hate soccer. I hate Bar?a.
They talk about it like it's important.
Do you have your idea about politics?
I think they should bring the guillotine back.
I don't understand why kings exist.
If we can put them up, we can eliminate them, too.
I'm sick of politicians who earn three times more than my mom,
who works all day at the bar.
I'm sick of the fucking TV. The more stupid, the more famous.
But if you have two jobs, you have to go abroad.
I'm well informed. I don't
need to leave home to know what's going on.
Great. But it's necessary. Let's go.
What? No.
and you have to go out on the street and face reality.
You won't do anything to change the world from here.
-I don't want to change it. -It would be just for a minute.
You know Socrates spent the day going to the Agora?
Do like him. Learn from him.
I don't want to go out. Because I can't. Damn it.
What do you want?
You want to grow old isolated from society, like Kaspar Hauser?
Or like the animals in cages?
I don't care what you say. I won't leave here.
Then, go to the psychologist.
Neither.
Your mother would prefer that you stayed enclosed in the cave.
Nothing happens to you. I don't feel sorry for you.
the more scared you get and the snowball will get bigger.
Don't tell me stories. I don't want to know anything.
Look at me.
Look at me, dammit.
I'll stick to you. Nothing will happen. No one will hurt you.
Just ten steps.
Then we come back home right away. Just ten steps.
Ten steps and that's it.
Do you trust me?
It is only fifteen steps to the tree.
-You said ten. -All right, ten. Little by little.
Try to lift the head and look forward. Come on. Head.
-I'm feeling sick. -We're almost there.
Calm down. Calm down. We're here. We're here. A little.
Come on, little by little. There's a step.
Be careful.
Coffee and cream?
Black coffee.
And water. Right?
Come on.
Excuse me.
-Are you better? -No.
-What did you do? -Oh my, what a drag.
You took him out without my permission.
If I wait for your permission,
your son will stay home for 30 years.
-How are you? -How do you want him to be? Intact.
Come, sit down.
Calm down. Calm down. Wait a moment.
Who do you think you are?
How dare you take him out of the house?
Miriam, you're overprotective.
-Can't you see? -He's sick.
Was it not clear from the beginning?
Is that how you help us, jerk?
If you don't let me do this, I can't help him.
Never come back to my house.
We're going home.
Come on. Easy. Calm down.
After what happened, we should
be glad you were suspended for only thee days.
They understand it was a one-time thing.
-Joan made a mistake and was punished. -Not completely.
-You don't let me go out with friends. -With Pol and Bruno?
Are they your friends?
It's obvious that I can't let you hang out with that rabble.
Jaume.
-Are you having a test soon? -Yes, Philosophy.
-Merli lets me do it after tomorrow. -Do you want more coffee?
-They speak very highly of Merli. -They do?
-He's the best teacher I have ever had. -Why is that?
Because...
Because he's funny. He explains things well
and makes me like the subject. Everyone likes him.
-It's great, isn't it, Aurelia? -Of course.
It's nice to have a teacher who befriends the students.
No, no, we're not friends. He just teaches us.
There'll always be a kid who doesn't pay attention.
But it's okay. No problem. Time is against you.
You read it and we'll talk later.
Thank you. What are you doing here?
-Hello. Shall we have dinner? -No, no, no and no.
I am working. You come, all of a sudden...
Okay. I do the same. But it's always about Gerard.
-Great. Are we having dinner or not? -No, no way.
You're going too far.
-I already told you no the other day. -No, you didn't say no.
I asked you if you liked me. And you didn't reply.
-To me, it was a yes. -You got nerve.
I thought we could celebrate Gerard's grade.
You raised Gerard's grade so we can have dinner, right?
No, sorry, no. I didn't do it for that.
Besides, Gerard will ask me to fail him again.
Impossible. You already gave him a B.
-How would he... -You'll see.
He'll ask me to give him back the D.
Are you sure of what you are saying?
I don't know. I'm nervous. What do you want me to say?
Then, will we have dinner or not?
Not.
Have you kept this?
Don't trust him. For him,
everything is relative. He's worse than me.
No, Merli. I've just ended a relationship.
No. Right. "And I'm not ready. I need more time for myself,
-I was hurt. I suffered a lot." -Yes, it's true.
All right, we'll see.
What are you doing?
-I'm going. -Yes, yes. Go, yes.
Goodbye, Merli.
"Socrates was Plato's teacher. He opposed popular ignorance
and those who considered themselves wise.
On the other hand, Socrates didn't consider himself wise.
He was a man who doubted everything.
Who cares what our parents put in our heads?
Do you agree with what you have received at home?
You are free to leave them behind."
Jaume.
Hey, have Toni come yet?
-I don't know. Is there a problem? -Yes, with Merli.
I read some of my son's Philosophy notes.
Merli tells the students what they have to think.
-Jaume, I don't think so. -I don't care. I have to talk to Toni.
I think you'd better speak directly with him. He's over there.
-It's him? -It's him.
Hello.
Merli.
-You're Merli, right? -Yes.
I'm Jaume. Joan Capdevila's father.
Great. I have a few visiting hours.
Yes, I know. But I want to talk to you now.
Great.
Joan has been weird lately. Something happens.
The test thing. His performance is getting worse.
But I've read his Philosophy notes and I figured everything out.
You question the values learned at home.
And that's indoctrination.
-Explaining Philosophy is indoctrinating?
-Yes. Your way of explaining is.
You say what parents have taught them doesn't matter.
You gave him ideas that go against what we have planned for him.
Have you ever thought that eventually Joan has his own plans?
He's too young to decide. And you have nothing to do with it.
I just want the students to think freely.
And that freedom has led him
to the faculty room to steal a test copy.
He was suspended for three days for that.
Forget about it. Turn the page.
I don't want to. I have
forbidden him to hang out with his friends.
He has been punished here. Why do you have to punish him at home?
-You see? You don't stop teaching. -That's not teaching.
I just wonder why you have to crush your son.
Don't you crush him by brainwashing him. Understand?
You asked what happens with Joan lately.
I'll tell you what happens.
He's happy.
He is happy.
-Yes, it looks great. -Yeah.
-Wow, girl. You look fucking great. -I do? You like it?
I have to give her credit. She sure has one hell of a house.
-Really? -Come on.
What is that girl's name?
-Monica. -Oh, right.
Monica, let's see when you can invite me and comb my hair. Okay?
Anytime.
My mother is a hairdresser, but I trust you more.
Look who's coming.
-Damn. What did you do? -Nothing.
-Wow, you're beautiful. -Yes, she is.
-Of course. -Not that much. I don't know.
Monica helped her.
You could open a salon and get rich!
Yeah. Sure.
Hey, handsome, we have Philosophy class.
Thank you. You are beautiful, too, Berta.
And you, Monica.
You three are natural beauties.
Man, I like how you recite Shakespeare.
-Thank you. -You do it really well.
Yeah, well... I have memorized many monologues.
Sure. Recite to me someday. Okay?
Sure. I like having audience.
Everything. Comedy, tragedy. Romeo, Juliet. Whatever.
-Julieta, Romeo. Eh? -Sure.
Sure.
He accused me of brainwashing his son. Oh my.
I just encourage them to have questions,
so they can think by themselves. I accompany them, Toni.
Isn't it what we teachers should do?
-What? -Nothing. I used to be like you.
I was closer to the students. I wanted to encourage them.
I don't know. Eventually I lost energy.
And you've become a boring teacher.
I didn't say that.
But you think so, don't you? Do you think you are boring?
In any case, I'm respected.
If the kid doesn't want to go out, you can't force him.
Okay, we won't go to the street. I'm going. I have class.
Wait. What about Gerard's mother?
She came to visit you one day and the other?
-What is it? -Yes, a big question.
She demanded that I gave her son a B,
because he knew everything well at home.
-No? No? -Yes. Yes. No.
It's unbelievable, unbelievable.
What are we doing with the teaching, Toni?
I have dedicated myself to this for years.
What the fuck is happening that parents now dare tell a teacher
how he should teach or what grade he should give?
-Yes. -Someday, if I ask medical leave,
it will not be because of the students, but of the parents.
It's for shit. Gerard's mother demanded me a B.
because I want to take her son out of the cave.
Joan's father accuses me of corrupting his son. Dammit!
Herod was wrong. It was not the children that he had to kill.
It was the parents.
-Hello. -Hello.
-How are you? -Fine.
-Do you want to meet tonight? -I can't. I have things to do.
Pity.
But hey, maybe...
you could call me. If I have finished, we can meet.
-Okay. -Really?
Okay.
Hi.
You know that in the end, he gave me a B in the test?
He made a mistake?
Well, I'd say Merli demands more.
He sees I like Philosophy and he asks for more.
-He saw that I deserved a B. -Then, congratulations.
Quiet.
Sit down.
Okay, we were talking about Socrates.
Remember he was the one who was accused of putting
ideas into the young's heads,
when the only thing he did was ask them to question.
I asked you the same thing. Be distrustful.
What if we distrust you?
Great. Perfect. No problem. Distrust me, but it'll cost you.
All right.
When Socrates was told
he was the wisest among the Athenians, he doubted, too.
Then he asked other wise men what was knowledge.
And he saw they didn't have a clue.
And what did Socrates do?
He concluded that, at least, he knew he didn't know anything.
"I know that I know nothing,
but at least I know something." Clear?
Athens killed Socrates
because he was a pain in
the ass who kept making irritating questions.
It's no surprise that Plato, one of his disciples,
distrusted the democracy,
which, as you know, was invented by the Greeks.
That's the problem we have today.
I mean, democracy is not perfect.
I won't answer you.
Wow.
What's wrong?
I've already given you the grade you wanted, a B.
But from now on, to me, it's as if you're not in the class.
What system did Socrates use to make people find out
that they knew nothing?
Maieutics.
-Gerard made a face. -Girl, I think he likes you.
He's talking to you all day. He's looking for you.
I noticed it. Just like you look for Marc, right?
In class, I don't hear anything.
I only think of him. Nothing else.
Hey, where is Berta?
I don't know.
-What's with you and Bruno? -He overdid it when he called me fat.
Yeah, guys are bastards.
Hey, someday, tell me your romantic stories.
Do you have a boyfriend?
Why don't we go inside?
Oh my.
-Tania. Tania. -Let me be.
Merli, wait. I want to talk to you.
Merli. I want you to fail me.
Give me a D again.
I shouldn't have asked for a B.
In other words, you plan
to leave the state "I want my mom to save me"?
-Yes. -I didn't hear you.
-Merli, man. -Don't call me "Man."
Okay, I won't ask my mom to save me nor will I demand a grade.
Okay, you got a D.
But you're back in class like the rest of your classmates.
Okay.
I don't like that most of you failed.
That's why those who flunked
will have an assignment which serves as a test.
But everyone will do it to raise their grades.
Fucking great. Thank you.
My dad came to see you, didn't he?
Yes.
I guess he didn't like your Philosophy notes at all.
Yeah.
Joan, I'm glad that you like my lessons.
And what we discuss in class makes you think about your life.
But the key is that you...
you don't know too well what you want your life to be.
But at least you know what you don't want.
I'm also not old enough to decide anything.
They make you think that?
-I don't know. My father thinks so. -No.
-I care about what you think. -Yeah, but...
-But what? -I'm not at the age to...
I don't know.
Come on.
Look.
What is this?
-A bill. -How much is this?
Fifty euros.
How much is this now?
How about now?
-The same, 50. -Then you're like this bill.
No matter how many times you're
stepped on or crushed, you're worth the same.
And I think you're worth a lot.
You're a Greek hero, Joan.
For you, I would sacrifice ten bulls
and organize the Olympic Games throughout the Polis.
All right.
Girl, I was told that you saw Marc and me.
We kissed a little.
I didn't want to. I swear he approached me first.
Berta, you two were making out. And you know that I like him.
Just two or three kisses.
And I made it clear I don't want anything with him.
He wants it, but I refuse because I know you like him.
Berta, you're a bitch.
-Leave me alone. -Tania, really...
Berta, please, leave.
I told you Berta was unreliable. But you didn't listen.
Why do you care about what happened to me?
To you, I'm just a fucking fatso,
just as you told me the other day.
Tania.
My mother says that to me, okay. But you? You're my best friend.
-I swear... -What?
-You're not fat. -Liar.
Lie. Yes, I am. Yes, I am fat.
I have flesh, I have fat. I have more fat than you.
It's not okay to tell a person who has fat that she isn't fat.
Because I am. I'm fat. And you compared me to that bitch Berta.
Okay. What do you want me to say? I don't know what you want.
Okay, you're fat. That's it. Happy now?
Yes, I'm happier.
Do you know what you are, man?
A fucking fag. A repressed fucking fag.
You won't ever have a guy
because you're a coward and a hypocrite.
Look at me. You're a hypocrite, Bruno!
Fucking faggot, dammit.
Say goodbye and go.
I won't say goodbye to him because I will keep coming.
You don't understand anything. Go away.
You pity your son.
-And look at him like he's a weirdo. -Enough! Get out of here.
I don't pity him.
I reprimand him. I make him laugh.
And I downplay the anxiety attack that he had on the street.
Is that little for you? He vomited. He couldn't breathe.
-And he can't leave the house. -Until when?
Tell me. At what age would you let him leave the house?
Now it is too early.
What about you, Miriam? Have you looked at yourself?
From home to bar, from bar to home.
Do you do anything else during the day,
apart from lamenting and working?
You're a pitiful soul.
Either both of us are positive and trust him,
or within a year we will have the same conversation.
You are isolated, imprisoned in your job.
But you're a beautiful woman and could take on the world.
Have some fun. Go out.
You're choked up at home, too. Free yourself from your child.
And I assure you that
eventually he'll go to school by himself everyday.
-Hi. -Hey, handsome. Lost your group?
-Are you Gina? -Yes.
A gentlemen told me to give you this.
-Thank you. -Good-bye.
I wait for you at the entrance of the flooded forest - m
-You are not okay. -Hello.
I just saw a fish that looked just like your son.
Skinny, hectic, with the "Everything goes wrong with me" Face.
Are you making fun of him?
Like I said, he asked me to flunk him.
But he can do an assignment to raise his grade.
And that depends on us having dinner together?
For example.
Then flunk him.
Forget about Gerard for a moment. You and me are here.
You don't want dinner? Okay.
I want to spend the afternoon with you.
Walking, strolling around the park,
going around, then drinking something.
Then come to my house.
You can't invite me to your house. You don't live alone.
No, Bruno is doing after school
activity until evening and my mom goes home late.
I'm like a teenager who knows when the house is empty.
You always get away with it, don't you?
You sent a child to me with a message.
No doubt you're not well in the head.
The one who's not well in the head is your ex.
He left you for another woman.
Hello.
-What is it? -Open it.
A hundred pesetas.
The first payment of my father.
He always kept it like a treasure.
And when I graduated law major, he gave it to me.
It was a symbolic prize for my effort.
I want you to keep it.
I know that you will try as hard as your grandfather and me.
And you'll have your own lawyer office.
But...
But what?
I don't want to.
What?
I mean...
I don't want to lose the bill.
I trust you.
Keep it well.
Will you do it?
-Enough. I had two. -So what?
I have to say this is not a real date.
No, of course not. It's a fake.
Excuse me.
Does your mother work?
Great actresses never retire.
-Actress? Who? -The Calduch.
Carmina Calduch is your mother?
I've seen her acting. She's great.
-She's the best. -You didn't tell me that.
I want you to appreciate me for me, not for my mother.
You're an actor, too, a little. You sent the kid with a message.
If Gerard was as skillful as you are,
Yes. She's pretty. I think she smells nice, too.
Smell?
-Yes, women have a scent. -Men, too.
But men are like wolves. All have the same smell.
No nuances. No. You women give off
a special kind of pheromone. A scent.
Come on. What scent do we have?
Sometimes, it's hard to know a woman's scent.
The perfume spoils it.
Like hot chocolate.
I don't want to keep up this conversation.
Today I don't wear perfume.
Merli will return.
But we won't go out any more.
Until now, we were alone in this.
Merli is helping us. You wanted him to be your teacher.
Inside the house, yes. Not outside.
You saw how I was. I couldn't breathe. No.
I know. I know. But I want to ask you a question.
Are you better now than the day Merli came?
I'm terrible, mom. You and everyone can see that.
-You are not answering. Are you better?
-I'm better here. At home.
Relaxed, no attacks, no fucking panic attacks.
It's a very simple question.
Are you better now than when Merli came?
Yes.
Don't move. Don't move.
Stop, stop, stop.
-Macadamia nuts. -Macadamia nuts?
Come on, please.
You're Gerard's teacher and you're smelling me. It's surreal.
It's not what teachers do with students' mothers.
I'm going.
What are we doing?
Live, baby, live.
We were friends, or so I thought. I don't know.
She wants me to believe that he started it.
She likes flirting around.
Yes. When a guy approaches her,
she snuggles up to him until she fucks him.
You've been with many guys, right?
Some. But I only had one serious boyfriend. That's enough.
What happened?
Nothing. I don't care, Tania.
But if you care about your friend,
you should fix things with her.
Yeah, you're right.
I'll talk to my best friend.
What a bitch! I went out on the street and Eugeni caught me.
The other day, you went overboard with Marc.
Someone hurt you and you keep silent. Who hurt you, Berta?
Merli is the master. No wonder he is dating the English teacher.
-What? -Yes, with Laia. Pol told me.
The one who's so gorgeous.
Yes, beautiful and super young. She could be his daughter.
What about we do the Philosophy assignment together?
Yes, I'd love to.
Then tomorrow afternoon, I'm free and no one is at home.
Today you fuck her.
There's a new girl in class, right?
You like her?
I'm shocked.
It's all right, Bruno. The world is full of fags.
Dad, you're crazy.
You shouldn't give a shit about what people think of you.
Shut up, shut up! No, no!