His masterpiece "Loneliness", from 1905.
-I am the master. I'll get ten points.
-Well, we have the questions.
We should hide that fact in the test. An eight is enough.
-No, man. -No?
We have the questions. Let's go for a ten.
Why don't you tell me how you got this?
-I can't. -I can imagine who helped you.
You'd better sleep here. We have to study until late.
I argued with my father
because he didn't want to pick up my grandmother.
-Isn't she his mother? -She is on my mother's side.
She surely has asked for me.
Let's go.
Hey, a selfie. Studying to get a ten.
"Cheese!"
Damn, my favorite student in my house, and in pajamas.
-What do you want, dad? -Nothing. I just came to say goodnight.
-You don't need to. -Then, go. Study.
-Close the door. -Yes, so no one can see you.
-So, let's sleep? -Go ahead. I'll review this.
You haven't made out with a girl in a long time, have you?
-A year or so. -You should get another one soon.
At the moment, I don't like any girl.
-But you don't ever stop. -I can't complain.
How many girls have you been with?
Pol...
It's that I...
You, what?
I'm sleepy.
I'll go to sleep.
Actually, Bruno didn't want to leave.
He told me, when you were gone. He just wanted to tease you.
He is a bit like you.
Listen, that boy, Pol, is he the son of that woman you like?
Where did you get the idea that I like someone?
You were happy when you told me that you met a student's mother.
When you talk about students' mothers, it's never something good.
-You get it, eh? -Are you still with Laia?
Yes.
With Gina, it's different. Things go at a slower pace.
Gina! Sounds good.
But it surprises me that you are so slow.
Soon everything will speed up.
I'll tell her I'm attracted to her and that I like her very much.
Now you remind me of your father.
-You haven't talked about dad for years. -That Gina is promising.
What are you doing?
I just took your notes, so they don't bother you.
-Did you touch me? -No, man!
-I'm leaving. -Pol! Pol! I didn't touch you.
Now I know why you don't hook up with any girl!
Okay! I did touch you, but it was a joke, Pol.
I swear.
-Can I sleep in peace? -Sure!
Your father's first payment has arrived.
Cool.
But it's not what we had agreed. Your 200 euros are missing.
-He transferred it to me. -What?
I asked him to. It's mine. I want to leave it in my account.
No, you are not 18 yet. You cannot manage a pension.
The pension you charged already includes my expenses.
This one is a bonus, a kind of allowance dad gave me.
You call him dad, now? How intimate.
I don't want to see him. I just care about the money.
Transfer it to me now. I'm the one in charge of the money.
-If you don't, I'll report it. -I asked him to do it.
No. That's not what we agreed to.
I don't want you wasting 200 euros.
You wanted to read dad the riot act, right?
You won. You have what you wanted. So do I.
I don't want you to have so much money, damn.
could make you understand? You listen to him.
Don't go to my school. The teachers will think you're a pain.
Okay. I won't go. Are you happy? I won't go.
But you have to transfer it to me.
You came to congratulate me again?
No, I came to ask for your help, if you don't mind.
No, I'm getting used to your surprise visits.
-How about your visit to the museum? -It was just a coincidence.
Sure. Listen, I got a pension of 200 euros for Gerard.
His father will give it to him every month.
-But he had it transferred to him. -So what?
He is underage. I should be in charge of the money.
Sorry for saying this, but I think you're a bit naive.
What?
What did you expect? It's his money, he won't give it to you.
He is no longer a child. I don't think I can help you.
You are a father. Would you give Bruno 200 euros a month?
-Don't be crazy. -So why did you call me naive and crazy.
You got yourself in this mess.
You wanted to exploit your ex, right?
You had what you wanted. But you didn't foresee this detail.
Shall we go to the bar next door and talk calmly?
I don't think so. I'm leaving. Don't tell Gerard I came.
Pol Rubio, as always, the first one to finish.
-Pol, how did it go? -What do you think?
You handed it over too soon. I think Hitler will suspect.
Let him suspect. I did study.
I know that you studied. Listen, last night it was a joke.
I don't know why you put it that way. We are friends.
As long as you don't touch me.
So, according to Aristotle, man is a social being.
Which certainly will be on the test.
-But... -It is too much!
Keep silent. According to Aristotle,
without friends, you can't reach eudaimonia.
In Greek, eudaimonia means happiness.
To Aristotle, life's goal is the pursuit of happiness.
Nowadays, we have turned it into an unhealthy obsession.
We think it is a right we have, not an aspiration,
and that leads to frustration.
Some say happiness is in little things.
The new fad is to talk about the coffee's smell,
about the singing birds... Bullshit. That's not happiness.
Who in here is happy?
Gerard.
Well, I am. In general, everything is going well for me.
-Good. -But not always.
-In general? -Yes, in general.
To Aristotle, happiness is not a state. It's an activity.
It's only at the end of life
you can say whether you are happy or not.
Do you want to be happy? Aristotle says you have to work for it.
-What? -That we have to work for happiness?
Work is fucking slavery.
Just look at people getting
on the subway everyday, they look miserable.
I don't know. Can you be happy working?
You got half a point in the exam.
Let's go, bull!
That's what I want you to do. Thinking. Questioning.
For the next class, you have to write on a piece of paper
what do you think of happiness.
-Does it have to be long?
-It could be one sentence. And anonymous.
Gerard, take this. Because everything is going well for you,
you're in charge of collecting the papers.
-Can you change it on Thursday? -Again, Gloria?
It would help me a lot.
I'm in charge of something else on Thursday.
But we had agreed that on Thursday. Another thing, Gloria.
-Yes. -How many copies did you make?
-For your exam? -Yes.
-Twenty five. -Are you sure? Because I counted only 24.
How strange. I'm sure I made 25.
-Are you sure? -Eugeni!
And when you left the copies at the staffroom, was anyone there?
Eugeni, it's impossible.
If someone stole the test, you'll know when you see the grades.
-Slow down. -Thank you, Gloria.
You can't be sure about it.
-Hello. -Hello, Joan. Come in.
What's up? Tell me.
At the end, you didn't explain
the topic of justice according to Aristotle.
-And because it will be on the exam...
-Yes, I'll explain in class tomorrow.
Okay. Then, that's all.
Since you're here, sit down.
Look.
Justice is a medium term between two ends.
Each end is the injustice.
It is unfair that you commit injustice on someone...
or that you allow someone to commit injustice on you.
-Okay. -In the middle, is the justice.
-And without justice, there's no euda... -Eudaimonia.
-Have you ever been unfair to someone? -No.
Was someone unfair to you?
-I'll come back later. -No, I'm leaving.
We'll talk later, right?
Man, it's a classic.
I'm not used to reading these things.
Do you know if there is a movie about it?
Your mother came.
Fuck.
She is very worried about the money you get each month.
She asked me to talk with you.
What is she doing? Why did she come?
As always, I don't understand.
Gerard, look. I think you're right.
It's your money and you can do whatever you want with it.
I will just tell you one word. Sophrosyne.
In Greek, it means moderation.
Now, leave. I had enough of teenagers for today.
"Sophro...
-nesis"? -Sophrosyne.
Okay.
Hello.
What have you bought?
-This brand is very expensive, Gerard. -So what?
-He told you? -Why did you tell him private matters?
Look who's talking. You
asked him for advice about how to fuck a girl.
Mom, please. Those words are not words a mother would say.
What do you know about it? I'm young, too, and I say what I want.
The fact that you talk like that surprises me.
No one can tell me how to talk, let alone a kid.
The money is mine and I can do whatever I want.
He told you that?
You manage your money. I'll manage mine.
-Kid, how was the exam? -Fine. Goodnight, grandma.
I suppose you don't expect
me to clean up your friend's bed, right?
-No. -Goodnight.
Goodnight.
Pol and Bruno's exams are perfect.
Someone has stolen the Catalan exam.
Wait. They have perfect grades and you think that...
I asked Gloria to make 25 copies. She left them in the staffroom.
When I counted them, one was missing.
At that moment, I didn't care much.
But she told me when she
left the copies on the table, at the staffroom,
there was only one person there.
-Guess who. -Come on, Eugeni. We don't have time.
You know perfectly who I'm talking about.
I corrected Bruno and Pol's exams and they got perfect marks.
What if they did study?
Come on, Toni. I'm not naive.
You know what kind of student Pol is.
And Bruno never gets more than a six. To me, it's very obvious.
The father took the exam, gave to his son.
Then, he shared with a friend.
-I don't know. I don't know. -What don't you know?
-Do you have any evidence? -Do you need more proof?
Did anyone see him take the exam? I can't accuse him like that.
I also think that he may be guilty.
But let's be serious, Eugeni. I will investigate.
You will investigate.
-What a surprise! -Why did you tell Gerard I came?
I asked you to keep it secret.
I don't want you to come between me and my son.
Much less to put him against me.
I see that I'm no longer a brilliant teacher
but the contrary.
You're funny, really. I think it's nice that you help him.
But I don't want you to boycott me as a mother. Are we clear?
Crystal clear.
Do you have a piece of paper?
-Yes, this is good. -This?
It's my phone number. If you have any other complaints, call me.
So that Gerard won't see you here.
I'll consider it as one of your outbursts.
Congratulations. You've got perfect marks in Catalan.
Pol, this is the first
perfect grade you've got since I've known you.
You went from failing to getting a ten.
-Not bad. -I'm happy.
You knew the questions on the exam.
No. We studied at my house until late.
We didn't want to fail again,
so we decided to try our best studying.
How come you took so much time to decide that, Pol?
I decided it now. So what?
You failed two classes. You could have decided earlier, right?
Well, no. I did it now.
Right.
So none of you came to the staffroom and took Eugeni's exam.
No.
Do you have any idea who it could've been?
Pol, you can go.
I want to get to the end of this story, Bruno.
Because I think you are hiding some information.
Did someone you know steal the exam?
Someone close to you?
No.
-So do I. -I don't see it clearly.
What he did in the exam is one thing, but...
I also think it's too much. Stealing an exam?
-He took Albert's girlfriend.
-Damn, Eugeni, what's wrong with you?
And Bruno got a ten. All fits.
Does it? It could have been
Come on, Santi. When Gloria
It was easy for him to take one.
It won't be the first time a student steals a test.
You know what is the most probable? That it was him.
What are you talking about?
We believe the Catalan exam was stolen.
How can you believe this man? The first thing he did here,
upon arrival, was breaking your relationship with Albert.
-Eugeni. -Be careful with what you say.
Forgive me.
If it is proved that it was him, then he can't continue teaching.
Right?
A copy of the Catalan exam is missing. They suspect you.
A copy missing and I must be the one who took it?
-Grandma gave me the exam. -Son of a bitch.
Toni cornered Pol and I, but we denied everything.
Now, they'll go after you.
She said she didn't. But why the fuck did your grandma do it?
-Because maybe she's like you.
-No one saw me. There's no evidence.
Dad. You're living evidence.
Who else can be a suspect, the janitor?
-Why? Did you two fail? -No, we have perfect scores.
You're idiots. You had the questions,
you should have played it off.
You could've tried a six or a seven.
And now we have to cover it up for you.
If you get out of this one, I will believe in God.
Fuck.
Pol told them.
I believe it. He is the only teacher who could have done that.
I told you he was a moron.
He can be cool with the students, but he can't fool me.
-He's the best teacher we have. -Sure.
What if Bruno stole the exam?
What are you saying, Marc?
Bruno isn't capable of stealing an exam.
Bruno! You could have given me the exam.
What?
I would have done fucking great if I had the questions.
How cool of your dad. Stealing the exam from Hitler.
Are you a moron? Why did you say that?
My father hasn't done anything.
If you spread that lie, he'll get fired.
Tell that to Pol. He told us.
Where is Pol?
Oh, tighter. Good. Good.
Finally, someone who knows
how to fix the pants without pricking me.
I want her here in the next play.
Would you like to be my personal assistant?
Yes, of course. It is an honor to me.
Honey, an honor? How classic.
Yes, it's me. You have the balls of a Prussian officer.
Girl, leave me alone.
Smoking is not allowed in here.
Do you mind putting out the cigarette?
Oh, how cute. Why don't you go fuck yourself?
You gave Bruno the exam.
That kid sometimes forgets what a secret is.
I did it so he wouldn't go to Rome.
It didn't occur to you that you
should have told him not to get a perfect score?
He could've thought of it himself.
I don't know what's wrong with this family.
We're always drawing attention to ourselves.
Okay, I'll say I was the one that stole the exam. Period.
-Did someone see you? -No one.
Didn't you say you don't want problems but solutions?
The solution is to confess.
No way. You won't confess anything.
Everyone thinks it was me. No one else could have done that.
I'll talk to Toni, I've decided.
Do you want to lose your son just like you lost your job?
Listen to me as if it was the last thing you did in your life.
The mistake has been made. Okay, we have to sort it out.
I will take care of Bruno.
-I will ask him to say it was him. -No, no, no.
Don't get Bruno into this. They will expel him.
It's the only solution. And listen to me.
Deny everything. Completely. And go further. Get angry.
Intensely. Defend yourself and say:
"It's a very serious accusation you're making against me."
Mom, you just recreated a dramatic atmosphere.
This is the only way you'll
get them to doubt what they already suspect.
You're always so dramatic.
Tell me if you didn't come here to ask for this advice.
-You told the whole class?
-What are you saying? I only told Marc.
Everyone knows. Do you want them to sack my father?
You should be happy because
I didn't say anything about last night.
I don't know how you got the
questions but you got into this because you wanted it.
If you bust my balls, I'll go to Toni and tell him everything.
Weren't we friends?
Not the way you wanted.
-What are you looking at? -He knows, doesn't he?
Yes, he does. You're a heavy burden in every way.
Are you calling me fat?
Yes, I am. You're a fat bitch who won't stop stuffing her face.
Toni, I'm shocked that you accuse me without evidence.
-I'm only asking you. -No, you're sure that I did it.
Who do you want me to suspect? Eugeni doesn't like you.
He didn't like you since the first day.
Gloria swears when she left the copies,
you were the only one in the room.
And why is everyone so
sure that there were 25 copies instead of 24?
Bruno got a perfect score.
So did Pol. Before, they had only bad marks.
Damn. They went to your house to study. Everything seems...
There is no evidence because
it is impossible. I didn't steal anything.
If you did it, you would have no right to continue teaching here.
Don't you believe me?
You don't need to threaten to fire me. I'm leaving now.
-Wait, no. -No, I will give my last class today.
No. I can't go in the staffroom
knowing everyone thinks I have stolen an exam from a co-worker.
Someday, you will know the truth.
And will understand you have wronged me.
-I thought of you today. -Raspberries, I know they are expensive.
Only for today.
I see you're upset about the exam thing.
I've made a mistake giving it to you.
Your father didn't want to do that.
But you had decided to go away.
He stole it, didn't he? He has to pay for it.
No, you're right. He has to confess.
Yes. So this nightmare will end.
Another teacher would come. More boring.
I am so sorry.
He'll be unemployed again.
Hard times are on their way. You'll be suspended for a few days.
-That's not bad. -No, it's not.
Compared to what they will do to your father.
I don't want him to be unemployed, Bruno.
Neither do I. But what do you want me to do?
You can't think of anything?
Grandma, take it. I don't want them poisoned.
You deserve an Oscar.
They will open disciplinary file for you, at most!
I won't confess that it was me.
I didn't force you to be a criminal.
But you did benefit from it.
You were so happy with your friend studying here.
Assume your part of responsibility.
And he should assume his. And I will no longer see him at school.
Is that what you really want? Your father is happy at work.
He needs to do that. It is his passion!
It's true that he made a mistake.
Maybe, he doesn't deserve it.
But I ask you to do this for your dad.
Bruno, say it was you and everything will fit.
Come on.
Come in.
Nice shirt. Is it new?
Yes. It's new.
Well,
I guess you know about what happened with Eugeni Bosch's exam.
I have to tell you that today is my last day here.
I can't allow the principle to suspect that I stole an exam.
It would not be good for either you or me.
But be glad, this isn't the end of the world.
-About Eudaimonia... -Wait. You're leaving?
Yes, it is decided Gerard, can you give me the bag?
Thank you.
Let's see what you think about happiness, peripatetics.
"I would be happier if my father stopped annoying me."
Bruno, I'm touched.
Well, this says:
"Happiness is impossible to get". Wow!
"I was happy when I was little." Not bad.
This one is not anonymous, and it says:
"Without money, life sucks. There's no happiness." Pol Rubio.
So, you'll sit here waiting to win the lottery or what?
I have won the lottery, but not the one with money.
Which one?
The family I have. We don't choose them.
You're right about that.
But Pol, there are families who have money and they aren't happy.
Have you ever wondered how
it would be if you were born in another family?
I'm surprised. He tells you anything and you believe him. Bravo.
Don't you see he made himself the victim?
He said he would stop teaching, let him leave.
Will you teach Philosophy?
Talk to the department. A teacher just quit.
I need this to be solved as soon as possible.
I don't want this to affect the students.
Do you really think it wasn't him?
I think it could be him but I have my doubts.
You have doubts?
Excuse me, Toni. A student wants to talk to you.
Now?
About the stolen exam.
I want you to understand that if you don't trust me, I'll leave.
-Listen, no. -No, I have decided.
The culprit confessed. I've just talked to him.
Finally, it is clear that it wasn't me.
If a student tells me it was him, I have to believe him, don't I?
-Hello. -What a surprise. Do you live here?
There is a meeting for the PTA.
I heard a rumor about the Catalan exam.
I came to support you.
It's been sorted out. There's no evidence against me.
-Really? -Are you surprised?
Yes. Bending the rules is your style.
Although, this time, I thought you had gone too far.
With my daring style,
I want to say that I'm attracted to you.
Yes, I got nerve. I already know that.
Yes, it is true. The word nerve fits you perfectly.
It's inappropriate. We are at school.
Am I the only one to think this way?
Any place is good for me to tell you I like you.
-Gina. -Hello.
-Are you going to the meeting? -Yes, I'm going. See you.
You know what? There's a
wide-spread tendency for hiding our thoughts.
Life would be simpler if we didn't try to complicate everything.
There are people, many people,
who like someone but they don't say it.
Why don't you admit that you like me, too?
No, I will not answer that question. Please!
The fact that we get along is one thing. But another thing...
How dare you? Let's pretend this never happened, okay?
Look.
I have seen this movie.
Yes, you have seen it many times. I'll put it on. Okay?
Okay, yes.
This town is getting colder and colder.
Hello.
-Why didn't you answer? -I didn't hear you.
Dad hasn't returned from Tarragona?
He called. He said that factory will pick him.
For three weeks, only. I don't know if it's worth going that far.
At least he is trying something.
I'm hungry. Is there anything to eat?
Make yourself a steak.
Do you think it's funny the fridge is empty?
If you know it's empty, then, why did you ask?
-Why didn't you go shopping? -With what money?
Work and the fridge will be full.
-You're so annoying. -I'm the only one who brings money home.
-I've killed myself working... -Working with what?
You're like dad when he had a job. Do you want to be the hero?
Dad gets unemployment payments and mom's pension.
He earns shit from both, Pol! Stop studying.
You never pass anything.
Hey! Rosaura said that there
won't be slaughter in the village this year.
Okay. I'll call Rosaura, granny.
Let's watch a movie, granny.
-Hello. -Hello.
Listen, Bruno, I appreciate what you did today.
What did I do?
You told Toni that you had stolen the exam.
-Wasn't it you? -No.
Grandma wanted me to save you, but...
I wouldn't confess to something I didn't do.
So, who was it?
You stole the Catalan exam? I don't believe it.
You don't need to do that. You have excellent grades.
Mom, I didn't do well in the first exam. I got a six.
Son, but what have you done? I don't believe you stole an exam!
-The staffroom was empty. -Someone forced you.
No.
That couldn't have been your idea. Who are your friends?
The same you know. This has nothing to do with anyone.
I was tired of studying so much and...
-I won't do it again. -Don't tell dad.
He will know, anyway.
Toni will call you. I have to stay home for three days.
Go get your father. It's dinner time.
-Dad. -Yes.
-It's dinner time. Are you coming?
-Of course. But come here a minute.
Do you see how beautiful it is? It will be the best model of all.
Look at the mainmast. It gives balance to the sails.
And the distance from bow to stern. It was all thought with care.
No piece is missing.
It is perfect. I'll finish it in five days.
Go to the dining room. I'm coming.
No.
I have a Philosophy exam next week.
-Do you need help to study? -Why?
Don't I help with your homework sometimes?
I'll buy the clothes I like with my money.
All right, sounds good.
-You are not against it anymore? -I only ask you to be careful.
She doesn't like the shirt. She likes you in the shirt.
-Again, what do you know? -I know.
-I don't believe it. -Stop thinking she doesn't like you.
I'm not the only one who likes her.
I know that there's someone else.
Just like that? I like you? People don't say that.
Women like when men say those things.
Even more if that's the man we like.
Yes, two afternoons are enough for me. I'll let you know.
Good bye.
Moron. Tomorrow, I'll have to go to the office earlier.
What a good smell. Do you know how much you scored in Catalan?
-Not yet. -Will you have the Philosophy exam soon?
It's different.
Just like him, a different teacher.
That doesn't mean he's better than others.
Believe me. I have experience.
You haven't seen him in a long time.
Yes. His son studies law. And in the afternoons,
-he works with his father. He's 22. -Dear me.
You'll have the same privilege. Before finishing university,
-you will help me at the office. -What if I don't get in?
With your grades, sure you'll get in.
The minimum grade isn't high.
-For Hispanic Philology is lower. -Again with the Philology.
What's wrong? Don't you want to be lawyer?
You told me you like studying laws.
Jaume, let him be. He's just in first year.
At his age, I already knew what I wanted to be.
And my father was not a lawyer. I had to build my own career.
I have stomachache. I'm going to bed.
-What are you saying? What's wrong? -Let him be. Let him rest.
Jaume...
If I tell you something, promise me you will be understanding?
Whoever was the student who saved you,
you'll have to look after him.
He sacrificed for you. You are a mythological hero.
These heroes don't exist anymore.
Joan...
Erase picture cancel
Do you know my father was a jerk to me?
It wasn't easy to get where I am now.
I don't want to be a jerk to you, Joan.
But I'll do whatever is necessary so you won't go astray.
In a few years, when you become a lawyer, you'll thank me.
All teenagers share the same story.
You complain about everything, but when you get older
you end up thanking us.
I respect what you've done.
Forget about hanging out with your friends. Is that clear?
For more than 2000 years,
the power tells us what to do and think.
They want us submissive and silent.
Well, go to hell.
What if your gesture is useless, Joan?
You sacrificed yourself for me. Is it worth it?
Is it right that a teacher become friends with his students?
No, we are not friends. He teaches and that's it.
Gerard, you deserve a three, but I gave you a four.
I think you mark according to the student.
Are you telling me that the grade I gave
to Gerard has something to do
-with me hooking up with his mother? -Yes.
-Man, I love how you recite Shakespeare.
-Yes, I know a lot of monologues.
-Someday you can recite me one.
-I would love to have an audience.
Romeo, Juliet. Really, whatever.
Please, leave now.
So, will we have dinner or not?
No.
Don't tell me anything. I don't want to know anything.
Only ten steps.
What did you do? You took him out without my permission.
Don't ever come back to my house.
You question the values learnt at home.
And that's indoctrination.
I just want the students to think freely.
That freedom led him to the staffroom
-to steal an exam. -I just wonder why you have to crush him.
You crush him with your brainwashing. Understand?