Merlí, I know I should not say anything.
-And I know it's none of my business. -There comes a "But."
But be discreet. I don't want any problems.
What are you afraid of, Toni? That we fuck in the faculty room?
Dammit, Merlí.
Excuse me. Merlí, someone to see you. The mother of a freshman.
Probably the mother of the new student, Mónica.
No, it's Gerard Piguillem's mother.
If she belongs to PTA, I won't go. PTA parents drive me nuts.
She might want to propose
some sort of activity on Saturday morning.
Merlí, please!
I'm kidding, dammit. I'm kidding.
Toni, you need some sense of humor.
-Merlí. -I have a visitor.
Just a moment, please.
It's just that I'm really upset. Everybody knows.
-It's normal. -Albert doesn't talk to me.
After what happened, you
wouldn't expect him to invite to eat out, would you?
I know, but I'm upset with this. What do you think?
Okay. Yes, I understand.
I don't know, do as you wish.
I think we could go on seeing each other.
Ah, you do?
Look, no. We'd rather not, Merlí.
Hi.
-Are you Merlí? -Yeah.
-The janitor. -Yes. I'm Gina. Gerard's mother.
I didn't imagine you like that.
I don't have much time.
Gerard knows I want to talk to you, but he doesn't know I'm here.
He freaks out when I come to school.
He says I only complain of the teachers.
Ah! These are Gerard's.
They fell down from the clothesline.
The neighbor leaves them on the stairs.
The kid doesn't use
clothespins because he says they leave a mark.
As if someone would see his underwear.
I'm looking forward to the end of this teenage phase. Soon!
I'm sorry. Have you come to complain about my classes?
No, I came to congratulate you. I'm sorry.
Hello. I hear you.
No, I don't intend to give in.
Talk to his lawyer and lie so you can get what I want.
Okay, we can talk later.
I'm sorry.
Well, yes, you're a brilliant teacher.
I thought fucking great that thing of the erotic poem.
-You don't mind I talk like that, do you? -No, no.
Lately, at home, things are just crap.
Too many mistakes, a bad environment.
Like puzzle pieces that don't fit. Gosh! What a shabby metaphor.
Gerard was pretty bad and your classes gave him a push,
-even though it's just Philosophy. -Sorry?
I mean, they're not as important as other subjects.
It's not Math or Literature.
It's more important than Math and Literature.
Yes! And it's fundamental to play the flute in Music.
I'm sorry. Are you upset?
-No. -I meant no harm.
Philosophy is important, I wouldn't say it's not.
Life, death, God.
"Man is the measure of all things." Heraclitus.
Protagoras.
True, true. One of the small ones. Yes, yes.
-Small ones? -Yes, the small ones.
-Those who came before Socrates. -Pre-Socratic.
Yes, yes.
The thing is that Protagoras was not one of the small ones.
He was a sophist. But anyway. Aren't you in a hurry?
-I pissed you off. -No, lady.
Remember, I came to congratulate you.
Gerard is delighted with your classes,
and I love seeing him happy.
And I thank you for that. I hope you go on like that.
I can't do it any other way.
I'm going to be late for work. Goodbye, Merlí.
Goodbye.
How did rich and powerful people get to be where they are?
Are they smarter? More beautiful? No. Nothing like that.
Machiavelli would simply say they are more evil.
If you want to be successful in life, trample on the others.
You will succeed in a dishonorable way,
but that's not a problem, as long as you get where you want.
That is, it doesn't matter who's ruling, but how they are ruling.
Exactly. Very well.
What do you think, Gerard? The ends justify the means?
Well, I think that...
I think that... it depends on the ends. Right?
Berta, do the ends justify the means?
What do I know? Do you think I ask myself this kind of stuff?
You're right. I'm the one who asks. Yes, speak up, Joan.
I was checking the subject's syllabus and that's not covered.
While we've missed other subjects.
Joan, my friend. Dammit. It's always the same story.
We have a teacher who's quite good and fun,
who does what he feels like.
We'll see the whole syllabus,
don't worry. But we'll see it my way.
I like mentioning other thinkers, though they're not included.
So, you can take your syllabus and,
since there's no paper in the toilets,
you can use it to wipe your ass.
Look, look. Look.
-Hi. Everything all right? -Yes, everything all right.
Come in. Good morning.
Well, I bring a new student.
Her name is Mónica de Villamore.
Did I say it right? Yes? Very well.
She's starting today. Come on. Good luck.
Hello, Mónica. You can take a seat.
Well.
-Wipe the drool! -Very well.
-I think I'm falling in love. -In The Prince,
Machiavelli considers
that the power of the state is above it all.
To the point that, in an extreme situation,
the ruler can resort to cruelty and deceit in a legit way.
What do you think? Mónica.
I don't know. It's tough
that a state can overrule law to defend itself.
Besides, why should it
dispose of our lives without any limitation?
That's an excellent reflection.
Man, I've fallen in love!
Come on! An office for Merlí!
I'm starting to think he's the principal's darling.
No way. He's offered himself to help out the students
who have difficulty in Philosophy.
It's just for four hours a week.
I've been teaching here for a long time
and I never had not even one hour of a private office.
What are you saying?
You're the head teacher. We share an office.
What are you complaining of?
Merlí has a privilege that I don't have.
When students have doubts, we sort it out after class,
or they should come to the
department's office, as it's always been done.
After what he did in the literary contest, now this?
And you didn't mention the
mess he's created between Albert and Laia.
What happened?
Laia and Merlí are hooking up. He stole Albert's girlfriend.
-My God. -That's private matter.
Toni, I understand that Merlí might be talented,
but to give him an office?
Talented? Talented? What talent are we talking about?
Somebody explain it to me, please.
Is it talent to take the students on a stroll around school?
One shows talent in class.
I don't dislike him, but it seems you forgive him everything.
No, no. I've been quite blunt with him since his arrival.
But I can't scold a teacher who wants to help the students.
You should prepare yourselves to help students who need!
-In the same room Merlí is using.
-Toni, I don't get paid for that.
It doesn't seem a bad idea.
But in the end of the day I
devote more time to students than to my kids.
Mireia, it's not a bad idea.
Okay.
We'll do it.
-Great. -We'll do it.
How are the classes with Iván?
Well, well, we've been reviewing a little bit of everything.
He hasn't spoken for weeks. Does he talk to you?
He only makes gestures or writes. It's something.
The same with me,
and I keep saying he should
see a psychologist. But he doesn't want to.
It wouldn't be of any help. One can't force him to.
I work all day long in a bar.
It's not that Iván doesn't leave home.
But he's obsessed with the Internet.
He spends all day long reading newspapers, or blogs...
-He reads newspapers? -Yes. And I don't think that's bad,
but it's somewhat sick. He wants to know everything.
Before shutting himself in,
he used to do that. I have a strange kid.
Yes. And on top of that, he makes a mess of the house.
If the house disgusts you, you don't have to come.
No. I don't care about the house. I don't mind.
And I don't care about the lessons.
But I want him to be able to leave the house.
I know he's got early agoraphobia, but we are on time.
We'll see.
You've got to trust Iván. And he has to notice that.
I'll pay you for the classes you've taught so far.
No. I'd rather be paid
by the end of the month. It doesn't matter.
I'll come by the house
before going to the bar and clean it up a bit.
No. Don't do that. He's got to do it.
You won't succeed.
Leave it to me.
Don't clean anything. Okay?
You're the only one to help me.
You liked the new girl, right? Your father freaked out with her.
Don't worry. You'll still be his favorite.
Marc Vilaseca.
A c!
Joan, your grades have dropped too much, lately.
-What happened to you? -I don't know.
Come on. Make an effort, you can do better.
-A C plus? What's the problem with you? -Leave me alone.
Pol Rubio, Bruno Bergeron, thank you for participating.
A damned D?
A D. This guy is picking on me more and more.
I thought I'd get a better grade.
Any problem, little Bergeron?
Question two is perfect.
I wrote what's in the book. And you gave me half for it.
You have a D. There's nothing to discuss.
Fucking shit.
Have you learned this kind of impertinence at home?
You'd better study harder for the next test,
-which is in three days. -What?
How come? Three days?
-How come another test in three days?
-About the two latest themes.
Those whose work is up to date won't have any problems.
-Damned Hitler. -Fucking shit!
Pol and Bruno, do you want me to kick you out of classroom?
What's the problem of Hitler with you?
He has picked you as his target.
He picks on me because of my father!
Two teachers pick on me, fat Santi and Hitler.
No. Santi does not pick on you.
He doesn't? He makes me
fail whenever he feels like. And Eugeni, too.
He can't stand my father and makes me fail.
-He's jealous. Merlí is a better teacher. -Yeah. Much better.
If we fail the test, we'll fail the final evaluation, you know.
Too bad.
It's really bad for me, man.
It's hard for me to memorize stuff. I can't do it.
-I can't remember, Bruno!
I can't! -Why don't you come study with me?
Does it work for you to study with others?
-With Tania. We do. -Yeah. And between lessons...
We're friends.
Well, if you don't feel like, don't come.
No, no, no. To go to your place is a really interesting idea.
-Is it? -I have never been at a teacher's home.
See you later. A D in Catalan.
-Damn! Congrats! -Eugeni is picking on me.
There you go with this picking on you. Don't give me that speech.
He picks on me because I'm your son.
He's giving another test in three days, and I'll fail it.
Dammit! I didn't use to fail before. Talk to him. Do something.
Talk to him? But who do you think you are?
You are the one who should do two things.
To study for the next test and to accept that Eugeni is mediocre.
Pass it to me! Pass it to me.
I think Eugeni never fucks, man.
I mean it. If he fucked, we all would pass.
What do you think, Gery?
-The test. -What test?
-He's head over heels for this girl. -Her name is Mónica, okay?
Weren't you in love with Judith, of the senior year?
-Yeah. Like you were getting married. -No, dammit! Okay?
I want to be with Mónica de Villamore. It's crystal clear.
Well, there she is. She's got nice tits.
-I tell you. -Go talk to her!
Are you insane, man? What would I say?
Look.
-Go there and introduce yourself. -Sure. No fear, man. Go for it.
Shut up, Joan. You've never introduced yourself to a girl.
Man, it's your chance. If you don't go now... Come on.
Come on, go.
-Come on, come on, go, go. -Okay, okay.
Look, look.
"Hello, gorgeous. How are you?
Would you like to come to my place?
I've got something to show to you."
Hello.
Do you want the class schedule or...?
No, no, thank you. I already have it.
Aren't you hot with that... with that sweatshirt? No...?
No, I'm good.
-Very bad. Very bad. -No, man. Champ!
How did it go?
She said we'll talk later.
-Pol, help him, you know. -Me? Lately, I haven't done so well.
Go and ask for Merlí's advice, right?
Dammit, Joan, you don't talk much, but when you talk...
-Sure. Talk to Merlí! -Pol, can you read between the lines?
Tell me, how am I going to talk to a teacher about girls?
I don't intend to.
-Hello. -Hello, Gerard. Come in.
-Look. Do you like it? -Yes, yes.
-Or do you prefer it like this? -Man! Love it!
Why are you here?
I have some doubts about things we spoke today.
What... What was it? The question asked...
What's her name? Mónica. The new student, you know?
Yes, Mónica. That was a good question.
Yes. She seems very smart and mature.
Yes. And you fell in love with her.
What...? No, no, no. I didn't fall in love. No.
Come on, man.
Well, yes, she's adorable. But she doesn't care for me.
What can I do? I mean, I never had a real girlfriend.
Well, let's see. I did things, but... but I don't know...
You told us that if we had doubts we could come, so...
Yes. Doubts about Philosophy. Not about stuffing the old turkey.
-I don't talk about sex. -No, no.
No, really. I fell in love eight times and this is for real.
So naive.
Don't you have, I don't know, some kind of technique? Something?
-Technique? -Yes.
Seek advice from your parents.
Don't you get along with your father?
-I don't have a father. They split. -Obviously you have a father.
For me, he doesn't exist.
He cheated on my mother for two years.
He lied to us. My mother went through a hard time.
Easy, she'll get over it. I'm divorced, too.
Give my encouragement to your mother.
Okay.
Okay, I'm terrible.
You dared seek the advice of a teacher on how to flirt.
I'll help you with Mónica.
Perfect. Perfect. What do I do? Do I say something or...?
-No. Right now, you shut up. -Okay. Okay.
You've got to make Mónica show interest for you,
-the way I'm going to tell you. -Perfect. I'll listen to you.
-Shut up, dammit. -Okay.
You've got to learn this by heart.
Dammit!
-You're going to study at your place?
-Yes. And he's really interested.
-Bruno... -Tania...
-What? -He's not like you.
-That... You know. -We're friends, okay? That's it. Friends.
But you don't care for him just like a friend!
-You're upset because I didn't invite you.
-What are you saying? It's not that.
I just want you to be careful.
Be careful with Berta.
Okay. I see you want to live as a Malibu surfer,
but in piggy style.
Open potato bags,
sunflower seed shells, a bitten sandwich.
As Heraclitus would put it, everything is in motion.
This orange peel,
within a couple of months, will have an ecosystem.
Let's see this.
What about this Kleenex? Have you been watching porn?
It turns out that I like cleanliness.
I hope you can accept my peculiarities.
Out there is the world of the living.
Don't forget that you are part of it, too.
One day you'll have to come back.
Yes, kid. Yes. The world of the living.
How many lives do you think you have?
It is not a videogame where,
if you get killed, you still have more lives.
You have only one life here! Only one life!
Iván, I know you are listening to me.
Today, you won't be able to enjoy my class.
Besides,
if you look at your dining room,
you'll notice the computer is not there.
Son of a bitch!
You have a wonderful voice, kid. That was about time.
I won't give you the computer back
before you clean the place and take a shower.
Dirty!
And Angel Guimerà, 1845... One thousand... fourteen?
Twenty-four.
Shit! I can't remember not even that.
Is your father coming or what?
I suppose.
Philosophy is cool with your father.
It must be nice to have such a father.
At home, I'm the weirdo, because I go to school, you know?
Well, I failed twice, but... But I go to school.
What does your father do?
He doesn't have a job.
Sometimes he gets a temporary job to do some kind of shit.
Assembly line for a couple of bucks.
How old were you when your mother died?
Nine.
Dammit, too many questions, right?
My granny is fantastic.
She spends all day watching old Marx Brothers' pictures.
She's the best in my family. I adore her.
We live with her and, once you're in,
it seems you're living in the fucking 40s.
We were evicted from our rented place,
like it happened to your father.
-Don't you have a brother? -Yes, yes. The idiot.
We call him Oscar, too.
The family is what you get. Friends, you choose.
Do you have many friends on Facebook?
About 500. But real friends, 70.
Just like me. Does your father have Facebook?
Come on. He doesn't have friends.
Does he have a girlfriend?
Now I'm the one asking a lot of questions.
He's hooked up with Laia, the English teacher.
What? Laia?
Laia. She's a hottie.
-Who's this kid? -He's Pol, a friend.
-Hello, ma'm. -Hello.
Your place is very nice.
Neither the place is nice, nor I like to be called "Ma'm."
-I'm Calduch. -Yes, I know. You're an "Actor", right?
Actor? What do they teach you in school?
May basic general education come back, please.
-Actress. -Actress.
I saw you in a dip commercial. You were very well.
Beckett, Miller, Brecht.
And you go into History because of a dip commercial.
Hello, Gerard.
-What are you doing? -I'm studying.
I had an appointment with the lawyer.
We'll sign an agreement with your stupid father very soon.
Mom, please, don't call him "Father."
Look, I bought new clothes to celebrate. Take this, it's yours.
-Dammit, they've fallen down. -Did you walk Rufo?
No.
-Well, then. Go. -Okay.
Oh, yes. I met Merlí.
-What are you saying? What did you do? -Nothing. Relax.
-Just said that I was happy. -Well, I honestly hope so.
A new student arrived today.
Her name is Mónica, I think. Mónica? Yes, Mónica.
And you fell in love.
-No! No, no, no. -Sure you did!
-Can you tell? -I know you.
You've fallen in love many times.
And I love it. That means you're more excited.
Yes. But I don't want to give it out,
because she doesn't pay attention to me.
But you're the most handsome boy in school.
Mom, I'm not a boy. And handsome. I'm not handsome, either.
You are very cute and that's it!
Well, I'm the cutest kid in the world. Right?
There are others who underestimate us a lot.
Are we going to do that, too?
From now on, we are going
to think that we are worth a lot. Right?
-Merlí sent you encouragement. -What?
I had some doubts in Philosophy and went to see him
and along the conversation
I told him about the mess of your separation.
-But what are you saying, son? -I didn't give details.
What are you doing, telling a teacher our private issues?
You tell me to be quiet and you are the first to talk!
He said he's divorced, too, that you should not worry,
because you are going to overcome this. Okay? Come on, Rufo.
I'm happy to know everything is all right.
Yes, yes. And thank you for calling. I was really moved.
Yes. And that. We should find
a chance to go back working together. It's time.
Come on, honey. A kiss. A kiss.
Bye. Bye, bye.
A harpy. But I'd rather stay on good terms,
because she knows the profession.
Pass me the wine.
-How was school? -Very well.
Today I met the mother of a student.
-And it went well, right? -Yes.
-Why are you smiling? -Nothing, nothing. My own stuff.
The boy.
-Hello, handsome. -Hello.
-Your friend didn't stay for dinner? -No.
Man, what a long face!
Eugeni, the teacher of Catalan, gave him a D.
I never failed before and, because of dad,
the teacher is picking on me.
Obviously. A D.
What do you want me to do? I can't change your grade in the test.
Yes. Nor can you change your temperament. Obvious.
It's true. The teacher doesn't like you.
You could make something up to help him.
Like what?
I don't know. But do whatever it is for him to pass.
-Make the teacher have an accident.
-No, there's no need to go that far.
But you could become friends with Eugeni.
An accident. You're an instigator of evil. You're Lady Macbeth.
-Lady what? -Lady Macbeth. Shakespeare, son!
Lady Macbeth. How young I was.
-“I have given such... -There she goes.
and know tender 'tis to love the babe that milks me.
I would, while it was smiling in my face,
have pluck'd my nipple from his boneless gums
and dash'd the brains out,
had I so sworn as you have done to this!”
Police?
Talent.
Machiavelli says the things as they really are.
That strength is strength, violence is violence
and lie is lie.
And there's no need to hide it behind beautiful ideals.
What does it mean "There's no need to hide it"?
Definitely, Machiavelli defends evil to save the state.
Tell me, Gerard.
There's something that doesn't fit in.
Why is it important to save a state that could harm its citizens?
Is it worth saving?
If the ends justify the means, what is it that justify the ends?
That's the smartest reflection I've ever heard from a student.
Gery! Very well. You're the best!
Hello.
-I liked what you said in class. -Really?
Because if you don't understand Machiavelli from the start...
it's difficult.
-Do you like reading? -Yes. Very much.
And what do you read?
Well, El Poema del Mío Cid.
-That's mandatory reading in Spanish.
-Yes. But I like it very much.
Look, do you know this book?
Steppenwolf. Dammit, it sounds good.
Really beautiful. I can lend it to you.
-Yes? Well, great. -You tell me if you like it.
Okay.
-Bye. -Bye.
Merlí, she liked me.
Mónica talked to me and she lent me this book.
Well, I'm glad.
Let's see if you cheer up a bit,
because the other day you
were depressed with your mother's thing.
Yes, I know.
-By the way, does she work? -Yes. At CosmoCaixa.
-Ah, yes? -Yes.
I love sciences. Have a nice day!
-Thank you! -Thank you?
Thank you for what?
You do favors to others, but nothing for me.
Did you talk to Eugeni?
No, and don't insist. Eugeni causes me more rashes than tourists.
I have to be fucked off.
You make teachers your enemies and they fail me.
You see that it was not a good idea to have you here?
Just as it's not a good idea to have you at home!
-Bruno! -Dammit! You scared me, Tania!
-How did it go with Pol? -Fine.
And shut up before someone hears you.
Don't be mad at me. I just want what's best for you.
Yes? It doesn't look like. Between you and my father...
That's not true!
-“Be careful with Pol. He's not like you." -Don't mock me.
“Don't mock me."
Okay.
Pol has always shown that he likes girls,
but as a matter of fact he's in love with you.
I'm convinced you're going to live a great love story.
Is this better, my friend? Are you happier?
Can you explain to me what criteria you used to fail Bruno?
He didn't know what was necessary for the test.
Yes. Listen, Eugeni, don't make come true the saying that goes
that teachers usually pick on some of the students.
You and me can pick on each other.
Yes, but this shouldn't have anything to do with Bruno. Okay?
How sweet you are, Merlí.
I like that, because you
notice there are teachers who can face you.
Some hit you physically, others, fail your son.
So you admit you have unfairly failed him?
No. No way. I don't pick on Bruno.
He failed, that's it.
Tell little Bergeron
to study harder for the next test the day after tomorrow.
-Hello. -Hello. Have you seen Eugeni?
Just left.
Well, I'm leaving the copies of the Catalan test here.
-Bye. -Bye.
-Hello. -Hello.
Don't you have to go tutoring?
Yes, I'm leaving.
Take this.
A copy of the Catalan test
that Bruno will have the day after tomorrow.
-You see, you could have done something.
-I have it up to here with Bruno.
If he fails because it's my fault,
he threatens to go to his mother.
He's upset and says nonsense. He wouldn't go.
There you have it. I have just talked to mom.
-I'm going to Rome and maybe stay there. -What the hell.
You can't go now!
No? Mom is already buying me a ticket for tomorrow.
You have a test! Besides, your father...
No! No! Let him go, let him go! I'm tired of you!
You're in a giant hormone and it doesn't let you think clearly!
-Do you want to go to Rome? -Yes! So I don't see you!
Well, then, go and stop pestering me!
The janitor said a mother of a junior is waiting for you.
Thank you.
Don't thank me. I'm doing a favor to the janitor, not to you.
-Albert, please. -I wouldn't have come close to you.
Albert, I know I made a mistake and I understand you're upset,
but you don't have to treat me like shit.
-Tell me that in English. -Come again?
You know how I get when we're
fucking and you speak in English in my ear.
Talk to me in English.
Don't talk to me like that, least of all here.
You'd have liked that I said it.
I'm doing just like Merlí. I say the things in your face.
-Fearless, not biting my tongue. -Come on, please. Let's talk.
Yes. You want to talk to me, but you want to fuck him!
Laia, fuck you!
Gee. It must have taken you hours.
Computer
Now you're back to not talking?
Yes, man. Yes.
Your mother told me you spend
all day reading newspapers on the Internet.
What subjects are you interested in?
All
No. We can't talk about the real world if you don't talk.
You know what? I don't feel like teaching, either.
Do you know what I'd rather do?
I'd rather go visit a very nice lady I met the other day,
instead of staying here with Harpo Marx.
What lady?
Yes, man. I'll tell you.
Go to her
You want me to go so you can go back to the Internet.
You're a manipulator.
I like you.
Bye
Well, listen. I don't intend to go.
You only...
You only have one life.
-Merlí? -The mother of Gerard.
-Gina, yes. We talked yesterday.
-We did. So? What are you doing here?
Working. I'm the coordinator of educational activities.
-Really? -Yes.
Really? Very well, very well.
Strange how I never saw you around. I come here often.
-You do? -Yes.
-Have you worked here long? -Five years.
You say you come here often?
Yes. I used to bring Bruno, my son. Now he doesn't want to come.
-Now they don't want us tagging along. -Right.
Well... Listen, Gerard is a very smart kid.
Is he?
He's shown interest for my class. That says a lot about him.
On the other hand, his mother
sees Philosophy as a minor subject, right?
Yes.
Well, I'm sorry. But I wish you luck. I'd rather go.
No, no, I have a break now.
If you feel like, we can have some coffee.
There's a little veranda.
I'm sorry. I have an appointment. I'm sorry. No, I have to go.
We'll meet again.
-Bye. -Bye.
"What, Gertrude? How is Hamlet?"
"Mad!
As the see and wind, when both contend which is the mightier.
-In his... In his..." -“Lawless fit.”
Shut up! I knew it!
"In his lawless fit, he feels... He feels that..."
Listen, let's take five. I know, but right now I can't.
My memory would suit you well in the Catalan test.
-I'm not doing it. I'm going away. -You should stay.
The Catalan test.
Your father took it. He didn't give you,
because you're obsessed about going.
But I think that, since we have it...
-I could scream now. -Spare me.
You force me to be smarter than you are!
You have a high sense of ethics.
Over the years, one loses it.
And lacks sense of humor.
You should have more, now that you are in love.
-What did you say? -You never talk about it.
But you surely have a lot to say.
It's the same with your father.
-Is he in love? -I'd say he is.
-With whom? -I don't know.
It doesn't matter, as long as he is.
Enjoy it, Bruno.
Use the test and, above all, let love flow.
"Spread thy close curtain,
love performing night, that runaway's eyes may wink
and Romeo leap into these arms, untalk'd of and unseen."
Granny, honestly,
don't you think there's too much drama in this house?
There's one missing. I counted three times.
Why doesn't the janitor make the copies?
Octavi is still sick.
Nobody comes.
We offer them the opportunity to solve problems.
You know how kids are.
-You're a very good teacher,
Mireia. -You haven't seen me teaching.
I don't need to. I can tell.
Thank you.
I have to call the sitter, after this. I left the kids with her.
Is your husband at work?
Yes. He's a graphic designer, but he needs his free time.
What about you? Don't you need free time?
Listen, if you want, go make the copy.
Not now. Later. I'll make it.
Then I'll make the call now, if you don't mind.
Okay. I'm going.
I don't like that the other teachers look at me badly.
Especially Mireia and Eugeni.
No way.
-What about Albert? Did he talk to you?
-Let's not talk about him.
Are you all right?
You're very quiet. What's the matter?
Nothing.
Does it hurt?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Are you reading?
Steppenwolf. But I don't understand anything.
Mónica lent it to me.
You see how handsome you are, you fool. She likes you.
We're friends, that's it.
And how was it? Did you talk to her, or did she talk to you?
Merlí advised me.
Merlí told you how to flirt? Teachers don't do such a thing.
I asked him.
He's very self-assured. You know he likes sciences?
-Really? -Yes.
-I told him you work at CosmoCaixa. -You told him?
-Shouldn't I? -When did you tell him that?
-This morning. Why? -No, nothing. Nothing.
Read. Read.
Hello, Iván.
The house is pretty clean.
Did you do it yourself?
Today there were few people at the bar. I don't understand.
It was calm. Usually, I never stop.
Tomorrow morning I'll wake up earlier.
A supplier is supposed to come.
Mom...
Yes. Tell me.
A man... in the United States, was released from jail
because they found out he was innocent.
He was charged for the murder of a little girl.
He spent 30 years imprisoned in vain.
Why do these things happen?
Did you call me?
I have the questions of the catalan test
Wow! No kidding. How come?
I can't tell. Do you want to study tomorrow at my place?
Sure, man!
You can stay and sleep here if you want
“He who seeks to deceive will always find
them who allow themselves to be deceived."
Yes! I'm sleeping there and we'll have an a plus! Go, go, go!
“I don't follow Philosophy syllabi I haven't written.
You can use the syllabus to wipe your ass."
Are we supposed not to overdo it in the test?
A B plus is enough.
-No, man, no! -No?
No. We have the questions. We have to go for the A plus.
The other day, how many copies did you make?
-Of your test? -Yes.
Twenty-five.
When you left the copies in the faculty room,
was there anyone there?
Yes, Merlí was there.
Some people find comfort telling themselves that happiness
is in the small things.
It's really trendy to talk about the coffee aroma in the morning,
about birds singing. Bullshit. That's not happiness.
Merlí, are you all right? Do you want me to call someone?
A copy of the Catalan test was missing. You're suspected.
Since a copy is missing, I should be the one who took it?
Granny gave me the test.
You have the balls of a Prussian officer.
-Did someone see you? -No, nobody. But...
So you have to completely deny it.
I've decided to talk to Toni.
Do you want to lose your son and your job?
You turn me on.
How dare you? Let's pretend this didn't happen, okay?
-Did you touch me? -No, man.
I'm leaving.
Pol, Pol, I didn't touch you, man!