Hi. I'm leaving earlier than expected.
I'm going to Rome today. Company things.
Can you stay with Bruno?
It's only three weeks prior to what we agreed.
Hell! Let's sit down.
Three weeks is no big deal. Bring Bruno today.
I wasn't expecting him yet, but whatever. I'll get used to it.
No, I'll talk to my parents.
He'll stay there until you're ready to take care of your son.
In three weeks, my parents will take him to you. I'll call them.
Hey, that annoying dog was licking my shoe.
You know how much that pisses me off.
I almost gave his owner a piece of my mind,
but I didn't because I knew you were coming
and I wanted you to see that I can control myself.
I will control myself with Bruno, too,
even if you're worried I won't take good care of him.
-I do worry. -Yeah, right.
But you worry less when you're in good company, right?
I don't have a boyfriend in Rome and do not butt in my life.
Is it so hard to tell the truth?
His name is Salvatore.
Do not tell Bruno. Work has nothing to do with him.
But he helped you find the job.
They didn't give me a position like this here.
-I have things to prepare. -Will you send the child support?
I never failed my son.
Damn!
Hey, listen.
Can you make man's fucking best friend shut up once and for all?
Tell Bruno his room will be ready.
I'll wait for him at home, 3pm.
-All right, three o'clock. Bye. -Bye.
When they told you to do an eviction, you must've thought,
"Damn, how boring," Right?
No, don't worry. I've known for a long time.
I would eventually have to live with my mom.
So, come in. This city is really great.
There are places for tourists,
but not for the people who live here.
You are going to your dad's house today.
-That's awesome news. -Bruno!
No! I could've had more luck: broken a leg and won at bingo.
Deep down, you guys are alike.
Don't worry about the dance classes. I'll pay for them.
Wow, what a change. You always opposed.
Bruno!
Your job must be very good.
Yes, it is. And I had a hard time accepting it.
-What? -You got a boyfriend. I saw your phone.
You looked at my cell phone?
Going to Rome for such a shitty job would be weird.
-It's not a shitty job! -As if it were something normal.
I asked you to come with me.
I can do without Roman adventures.
I can't go if you're angry.
When you get to Rome, maybe I'll be OK.
Wait a minute.
They evicted you.
Go ahead. Yes, yes.
But... Yes.
Yes!
Look, how old is the director?
Twenty-seven? Oh, tell him something for me.
When he was born, I was playing Antigone on stage.
I'm not an unknown actress! I'm the Calduch!
Tell me later. I love you!
Agents!
You rejected a job that would pay your rent.
I won't do anything but teach.
And Bruno? Wasn't he going to live with you?
The three of us here.
And I need to tame that director's ego.
He does Hamlet
with characters in military attire and thinks he's an innovator.
I like Bruno.
He's got talent.
Just one thing. He thinks
you work and doesn't know you were evicted.
Tell him the truth or you guys won't live here.
The peripatetic
Twenty minutes late.
The first "Merlinade."
I'm going to miss you.
Are you sure?
Of course.
Why do you change plans like this?
I would've arrived later if we'd gone to my house.
The meeting lasted longer than expected. What do you want?
-What? -Hi.
It's a joke, woman.
I'm sure we'll get along great. Yes or no?
Do I have to answer?
-You're walking with all this stuff? -Cab!
Thank you.
-Bye, sweetheart. -You're not going to cry.
If you hug me, no.
-Come on. Bye. -Bye.
Go or you'll miss the plane.
Yes.
-Stop, stop, stop. -What's up?
-Nothing. We must get out. Sorry. -What?
Let's get your bags. Get out.
What are you doing?
We have to save money, kid.
Can you try a little harder not to embarrass me?
I'm crazy!
Save your energy. You're going to go really crazy.
You fooled mom and me.
You have no home and no work. What now? Are we going to a hotel?
Bruno, I don't want problems. I want solutions.
Do you know why we came here?
Is this the solution? Living with the Calduch's?
It's chaos!
Hey! I am the only one who can be dramatic.
-You're at my place. I'm in charge.
-What? I'm in charge of my son.
There's no choice but to adapt.
No, sorry. Mom hasn't boarded the plane yet.
You know why I didn't pay rent for a year?
Because child support was my priority.
Your father can make a lot of mistakes, but he didn't fail you.
If mom finds out, she won't let me stay here.
-Don't tell her. -Let him.
-What do you mean? -He can do what he wants.
-Shut up! -You shut up!
Do you really want to ruin her trip?
You know she has a boyfriend there?
I don't care.
I don't feel like wasting my time arguing with a kid.
He says that for me.
Yes?
Yes, it's me.
Mom, we did not go to dad's place.
We came to grandma's house. What are you doing?
Shut up. I just got called. I got a job.
-Oh, you got a job! -What job?
Damn, son. Don't you remember? I'm a teacher.
Liar. You don't have a job. You're making this up!
You're giving me a headache.
That's your brain trying to understand your nonsense.
He's right.
-If you're lying... -I got a job.
All right.
Son, it's a lie, isn't it?
No, the school called me.
I'm going to be a substitute. I start tomorrow.
You don't look very happy.
How are you? I'm Toni, principal and Math teacher.
-How are you? -Welcome.
The last teacher got sick and will be on leave.
-OK, I can't say I'm sorry. -You will tutor our freshmen.
Tutor? Damn! So, I get to charge more,
and I can go out for pizza every now and then.
-I'll introduce you to the teachers. -Do you have to?
-Oh, of course. -The usual drag.
Gloria, the Art and Drawing teacher.
And Santi, her husband. Santi is the Spanish teacher.
-Nice to meet you. -Likewise.
We are married, but it doesn't look like it, right?
-Shut up! Come on. -Excuse me.
And Eugeni Bosch, head of staff, Catalan Language and Literature.
How's it going?
Welcome to the trenches. Are you the new Aristotle?
It was sung that Philosophy would be undervalued by all.
I was the first to post an article about it.
Interesting.
No, no. Eugeni has a blog on literature. It's okay.
I could interview you for the blog.
It'd be nice to talk about philosophy.
-How are you? -Hello. A pleasure.
Mireia is one of the promises of the school.
That's a bit much.
No, no, no. You're a diamond in the rough.
If you let yourself be advised,
you will end up being a great teacher.
Is there a toilet near or do I vomit right here?
Here are the schedules. Cheer up. Good luck on your first day!
Thank you.
-Hello, everyone. -Hello!
Hi.
I'm late.
I had to go to the vet. My dog was bad all night, poor thing.
-Hello. -Hello.
I had a really bad time. Gloria, do you have my photocopies?
-Yes. Here they are. -Thank you.
I like that name. I'm Laia, from English.
-I'm late for class. Bye. -Bye.
I'm sorry, but she's with Albert, the Phys Ed teacher.
I'm going. I have a freshman class.
What a way to start! Beware of Pol Rubio.
He's rude. Never takes notes. He flunked two years.
You will recognize him because he's always kissing Berta Prats.
Good luck.
Joan, do you have any pens left?
-Did I give you back the other one? -It does not matter.
Bruno.
-I'm so lucky. -Why?
I was going to live with my father,
but will live with my grandmother, too.
-Good heavens! -Bruno, my friend!
Why did you miss class yesterday? Were you sick?
Kind of. Yes.
-Today is the new Philosophy, right? -Yes.
-The new one of Philosophy? -The substitute.
What's up?
Nothing. It doesn't matter.
Good morning, kids!
He's my father!
-Seriously? Is he your... -Shut up!
and I want you to get turned on by Philosophy.
-Marc is turned on every day. -Shut up, you idiot!
That is, I intend to
contaminate you with my interest in Philosophy.
You. What's your name?
-Bruno. -Bruno what?
Bergeron.
Be... Ber... What kind of last name is that?
It's French.
Do you think Philosophy is good for anything?
-Yes. -That's what I wanted to hear.
I'm sick of people saying that Philosophy is useless.
It seems the educational system forgot the questions,
who are we? Where do we come from? Where are we going to?
Now all that matters is what company we open,
how much money we'll make.
Philosophy serves to ponder, to ponder about life,
about the human being.
And to question things.
Maybe that's why they want it eliminated, right?
They find it dangerous.
Philosophy and power have an unresolved sexual tension.
What is Philosophy?
-No idea, right? -Nope.
Philosophy is not just a set
of deep questions and absolute truths.
Philosophy is turning upside down everything we take for granted.
Good heavens, everyone with such a confused expression.
Not everyone, huh?
Contrary to what many people think, teenagers are not stupid.
-He is. -Don't rat me out, eh?
What happens is that they are asleep.
They don't lift their ass unless their mobile is taken from them.
I want to see you awake,
with your antennae on, attentive to what happens around you.
Ready to take on contradictions and doubts that life poses.
And to face adversities.
And, above all, since we don't always win in this life,
to learn from defeats.
I know a little about this subject.
Yesterday, for example,
they threw me out of the apartment I had rented.
Yes, yes! They kicked me out because I did not pay!
What a nerve, right?
You and I have two things in common, now that I think about it.
We live at mom's house and we do not have a euro.
And you say it so calmly, as if it did not affect you.
What do you want me to do? Should I cry?
No, I'd rather laugh at adversity.
Come on, tell me some personal problem laughing.
Who wants to start?
-You. Tell me, what's your name? -Tania.
All right, Tania.
My father was caught cheating the treasury.
-Yes, girl! -I swear. Now he has to pay a fine.
It's just that my father doesn't
know how to lie, he's sloppy. I don't know.
-Give him my best regards. -Right.
Not bad, but I ask you about you.
Come on, kids. Who wants to share?
Who else is encouraged? Come on, come on. You!
My name is Joan Capdevila and my problem is...
Well, I don't know if it's a problem, but I'm very shy.
-Yeah. But tell me that laughing. -I'm very shy.
But you raised your hand to speak in front of everyone.
You're not that shy.
Anyone else?
Tell me.
Always... Well, my name is Gerard.
I always like some girl, but they never look at me.
-Why could it be? -How do you know? Do you read thoughts?
This school may have
some girl who thinks of you every night before going to bed.
Come on, now me!
I do not take notes. I'm telling you, so you know.
I can't listen and write at the same time.
And no teacher understands it.
No. I do understand. Look, in Philosophy, you just have to listen
and learn to think.
I don't care if you don't take notes, Pol Rubio.
How do you know my name?
They told me you like to
study so much you usually do the courses twice.
Looks like you do not know him.
-It's not that... -OK.
I don't know him. I don't know.
-Yeah. -I cannot say the same.
Bergeron. Just a moment.
You should be happy. You see, I have a job. It was true.
Now you'll see how your father teaches.
-You asked for a job at my school. -No. This goes by number.
I cannot give up this position or I am deleted from the lists.
That's shitty. You giving me classes and mom in Rome with a guy.
She went to Rome to work, not to fuck.
Couldn't you delete the word "Fuck"?
And here. Mom will hallucinate when I tell her I'm going to her.
I will save and will look for an apartment.
It was enough to see you twice a month.
Now it's every day and as a teacher.
It is not my ideal as a teenager.
-Bruno. -What?
When I was a child, I left you and your mother. It's true.
I made a mistake. Don't you ever make mistakes?
Now I would like to help you not to make too many mistakes.
It's been years that I see you only a couple of weekends a month.
When your mom told me that she was going to Rome and that...
I had to stay with you, I was glad.
Yes, I know I am really used to going around free,
but I would like to live with you.
Dad, are you getting sentimental or what?
I'll leave you my room.
It's bigger than the one supposed to be yours.
If you want to be more relaxed, we won't say that I'm your dad.
I don't know how long it will take for them to know, but, yes.
We'd rather not say anything.
It's just that, dad, you're weird.
Everything okay?
-I do not like this mobile. -Okay, I'll buy you one.
Good.
What the fuck is this
adolescence that a father is worth a mobile?
Nothing. The vet did some tests and it's all fine.
After the night I spent, at least this makes me happy.
-Maybe she ate something bad. -I suppose.
Do you want me to come by your house today?
I'm very tired. I didn't sleep at all last night.
As you wish.
Well, come on. Will you stay over to sleep?
Yes.
How are you?
-Hello. How was the first class? -Good, very good.
Look, let me introduce you to Albert, of Physical Education.
-How are you? -Hello.
I'm going, or I'll be late for class.
-Fine. -See you later.
-Very well. -Bye.
-Is he your boyfriend? -Yes.
-How old is he? -Twenty-seven.
You are attractive to be with someone older and more experienced.
Why do you say that to me?
It's nothing. I didn't mean to bother you. See you around.
If he's talking to Joan, I don't know why...
He's a bitter one.
I couldn't stand David. I went to talk to him once...
He was an imbecile.
I looked for him in his office and you simply can't talk to him.
-He got serious, didn't he? -A lot!
You can't talk to him. Jeez!
At first I thought: "He's delirious". But then I liked him.
-He's worse than fat Santi. -No way! I like Santi.
The class seemed interesting to me.
-What's up? -Tutorials seem interesting to you.
What are you doing, man?
before coming to class. He sniffed glue.
I told him I don't take notes and he understood me.
-I understand you, my love. -Don't call me that way.
Stupid.
Do you want some grass?
It's going to fall on the food.
-What did you say? -Come on, shut up.
He's serious.
-You don't have a father. -Of course I do.
He asked your last name.
Yeah. And he laughed at your last name. Bergeron.
-Right. It was a joke. -Tania, whatever.
There's this guy, who goes to guitar classes with me,
who was so excited that he took a melon,
-put it in the microwave, made a hole... -No!
Then, pumba, pumba, pumba!
-He gave it all! -That's disgusting, man.
A guy, you say?
Why are all melons bored at your place?
No way! That's a lie!
Yes?
Hey, I didn't understand what you said about my boyfriend.
-Can you explain it to me? -Yes, I said he was very young.
I was surprised. Attractive women such as yourself usually go out
with more mature and experienced men.
Like you, perhaps?
I won't allow you to follow that path.
You've just arrived and I
didn't give you motive to try and seduce me.
-Is that clear? -Transparent.
Really, you're very gorgeous.
-But how dare you? -Are you insulted?
Is it so strange that I tell you what I think? I am like that.
When a woman attracts me, I say it.
And that doesn't mean that I want something more.
I just show my admiration for beauty.
-Thanks but no... -But no, nothing.
You're beautiful and that's it.
It won't hurt anyone to say so, will it?
I'm complaining about the tone.
The tone? The tone was correct. Sincere, but correct.
Look, whatever. Forget it.
Sure! Did you see the curriculum was not necessary?
I love you!
-Will you help me memorize the text? -Where is dad?
I think he won't come late. Do you like your bedroom?
I always dreamed of sleeping close to dad and grandma.
You'll get used to it quickly.
Yeah. Classes, not so much.
Yes, it's better that parents don't be their children's teachers.
-I'll take it stoically. -Poor thing.
Stoically. A word Dad put in my head.
Everything fine in Rome! And you?
It couldn't be better.
I'll call you tomorrow. Take care.
Okay.
-Don't you want some fruit? -No, I am not hungry.
-Hello. -Hello!
-How did it go? -All right.
-Do you want to have dinner, son? -Yes.
-They gave me the role. -Obviously.
We start rehearsals next week.
Listen. Is it true that there are people
who give dogs away because they can't take care of them?
Yes. There are many ads on the Internet.
You can't stand dogs.
He would never do it do not abandon him
Bruno?
Bruno, I'm leaving.
-So early? -I have things to do. Bye.
Dad.
No teacher tells his life story in class.
Don't make friends with the students. It's pathetic.
Look, Bruno, I teach like that.
And I didn't see your peers bothered. Yes? Bye.
Just a moment.
If you want, tell them you are my father.
But don't say I do dance.
Damn it! Fuck 'em if they don't like it.
-Dad. -Yeah, okay, I won't say anything.
It's very good. I loved your personal opinion on the novel.
-Oh yeah? -Yeah. I already told you.
You have a great critical capacity, Joan.
-Thank you. -You have it.
-Well, I'm going to class. -Yes.
-I'm a little late. -What have you got there?
Last night a friend called me.
He told me that they were going to put a few dogs to sleep.
-We're... -Yes.
Yes. It happens often. Me,
too. I have friends who work in kennels.
They gave me one. I could not resist. It's beautiful, look.
He's cute!
-And they were going to kill him?
Why? -Yes, you see. I don't know.
He's very quiet. I spoke with the concierge
-and he'll take care of him for me. -That's good.
You have to take him to the vet.
I know a very good one. Do you want his number?
Perfect. Actually, it was madness, because I cannot do that now.
Do you think he would receive me as an emergency?
Do you want me to go?
I know him well. I have an hour off in the morning.
-Perfect. Thank you, thank you.
-Come on. Everyone to class, it's late.
Do not turn on all the lights of the departments.
Let's save. Let us take advantage of daylight.
I'll leave it at my friend's
clinic and he'll call me when he has seen him.
-As you like. -Don't worry. You can trust me.
-What a beautiful thing. -Yeah. The dog, too.
Silence! Everyone to their seats.
Let's see, is someone missing in class?
He's a bit weird. He has not come for two months.
The freak?
All right.
This is my last name.
It was true! He's Bruno's father! That's crazy!
Bruno, if you're annoyed,
you'll stay home Saturday and won't go out.
Let's see. I don't feel like staying in class today. Follow me.
Do you think this is a joke? Follow me!
-Where? -Come on! Come, follow me!
Come on!
And so we get to one of the most important theater authors
of Catalan Literature of the twentieth century.
Does anyone know his name?
No one knows his name?
A playwright.
Good morning.
Good. I brought you here
because I find this to be an inspiring place.
The brain could be the kitchen of the human being.
And also to explain to you that,
more than two thousand years ago,
there were students of
Philosophy who were called the peripatetic.
-Pathetic. -What?
No, no. Peripatetic.
They were students of the Aristotelian school.
We will talk about Aristotle. They got that name
because they philosophized while walking.
Walk. Walk, walk. Walk!
Come on, walk, follow me. Come.
The peripatetic wandered while reflecting.
I don't know if you'll understand.
Come on. Ponder as you walk.
If you have an interesting thought, share it.
-I'm pissing! -I said an interesting thought.
Show your dick.
-You'd hallucinate with my dick. -Yes, sure.
Your father is getting weird.
-Shut up, girl! -What's up? I didn't say anything.
I was silent for two reasons. To think about the answer
and to show you that, when one thinks, people look at him badly.
Why is thinking frowned upon?
Shouldn't it be the other way around?
Isn't it more objectionable
when people don't reflect about things?
In Philosophy class, you can prove that you're rational animals.
In the other classes, you can remain just animals and that's it.
Come on, walk, gang of bipeds! Go! Walk!
If children went to class as penguins or dolphins,
now this class will be the class of the peripatetic.
Yes. You didn't answer me. Can everyone philosophize?
-What do you think? -Me?
I believe that if philosophy serves to question what we know,
everyone can do it, but it doesn't matter.
Not everyone wants to do it.
You've just become my favorite student.
-Come on! -Wow, man!
That doesn't mean the others cannot struggle for the post.
-I'm coming at you, my friend. -Easy, guys.
It was just my luck not to have listened to your Catalan teacher.
He told me to be careful because you are disrespectful.
Come on, walk! Think! Walk and think!
-Fucking Eugeni Bosch... -Think!
All right. Send it to me
by mail and I'll tell you something, okay?
-Hello. -What's up?
Eugeni Bosch criticizes me with the teachers.
Come on. That is not true. Surely...
-And they say he's not on to us. -Eugeni is not on to you.
He said to watch out for me and insulted me.
Go.
What? How did it go in the kitchen with the kids?
-All right. -It was all we needed.
All schools have the typical teacher who teaches creatively.
-May God spare me from being orthodox. -Yeah.
I'm more classical, I admit. I don't make friends with the kids.
I think it very important
to keep distance between teacher and student.
I'm more interested in the distance between teacher and teacher.
Yeah. Bruno can't find having you in class too enjoyable.
He's delighted.
I volunteered.
He has agoraphobia. He doesn't want to leave the house.
He seemed a bit weird to us, but he's a good student.
I'll do everything possible to take him to the street.
Yeah. When he sees you entering his house, he'll get out.
-What's wrong with him? -Nothing, nothing.
Laia likes puppies a lot, right?
A lot.
Is it so difficult to teach a normal class?
The concept of "Normal" Would lead us to an endless debate.
-For you, what is normal? -Normal is normal, Dad. Normal.
Damn. What a deep son I have.
Look, what is considered normal today wasn't normal years ago.
-It's a Foucauldian lesson. -Why do you always say weird things?
"Fucciana". What the hell does that mean?
Why do you act like that with my friends?
You were silent for three minutes.
And then that idiocy of thinking.
-You're jealous of Pol. -Oh, yes. I'm dying of jealousy.
Pol is very upset with Eugeni because of what you told him.
It doesn't surprise me.
Why did you tell him?
Listen, Bruno. Eugeni is the kind of teacher that I detest.
He believes students are his enemies.
When he enters the class, he looks for the evil.
-For me, they go unnoticed.
-Bruno, I'll wait for you outside, okay?
-Well, I'm going. -Fine.
I just ask you not to emphasize things.
You'll have to get used to having me as your teacher.
Bruno, my champion!
See? You will make more friends
being the son of the professor of Philosophy.
Dad,
I don't understand the peripatetic thing.
Can you explain it to me at home?
Wikipedia, son. Wikipedia.
-Can we talk for a minute? -Yes, of course. Sit down.
Listen.
Toni, how did you let Eugeni get in the home of an agoraphobic?
It's cruel, it's like Dickens.
See? You come in here and
you talk to me as if we were great friends.
You've been here for two
days and you are already creating problems.
Did you tell Pol Rubio that Eugeni criticizes him?
It's true. He criticizes him.
Students should not be privy to teachers' conversations.
Look, Toni. I can't stand that kind of mediocre teacher.
-I've met many, and they drive me crazy.
-Eugeni is a very good teacher.
No. He knows how to sell himself. He has no talent.
-Come on. Let's leave it here. -Let's leave it here.
It seems the kid felt detached from the group.
Occasionally, he wouldn't come to class, or was late.
Finally, he stopped coming.
His mother brought us the medical report.
He was diagnosed with early agoraphobia.
And he does not leave the house?
No, he doesn't want to
and he doesn't want a psychologist, either.
She is a single mother, works all day and...
In short, she can't take over.
I promised I would find a volunteer teacher
to follow up with the kid. Eugeni volunteered.
That will mean an aggravation of the illness.
He starts tomorrow. No costs, obviously.
How generous.
Yes?
Yes, I'll look at it now. Give me second.
Very well. Thank you very much.
Bye!
-Fine! Wow, what a relief.
-You can pick him up whenever you want.
Yeah, but I had to leave my apartment,
and now I'm temporarily at my mother's house.
And I haven't talked to her.
What will you do if she doesn't want it there?
I don't know.
Argue, I guess, because I'm
not going to abandon the dog in the street.
I was thinking...
and, if you can't care for him, I wouldn't mind keeping him.
But you already have one, right?
Yes, but I fell in love with that puppy
and I wouldn't mind having two.
-You'll have to ask your partner. -Why? I live alone.
-Oh yeah? -Yes.
It's perfect if he could stay with you.
In fact, you'd do me a favor.
-I got myself in a bind. -I'd be enchanted.
What if the two dogs don't get along?
-I guess they will. -Listen, why...?
Let's walk them in a park to check?
Good.
-Well, see you later? -Yes, perfect.
-All right. Bye. -Bye.
I must go back to the bar.
Do not force me to call the police. Please!
Out of order
Yes.
I'm from the Angel Guimera Institute. I'm the tutor.
We were expecting you tomorrow. My name is Miriam.
Was it not Eugeni?
-No, there must be some confusion.
-It doesn't matter. It's good you came.
I'll talk to him.
I must go back to the bar.
I manage the bar in front. I left a moment and I have to go back.
-Relax. I'll take care of this. -Thank you.
Toni told me not to pay, but I insist. Let's negotiate a price.
We'll talk about that later. Relax.
Thank you. If you need anything, I'm at the bar.
Yes, go. Don't worry.
From now on, I am your private teacher,
while you don't go back to school. Can you open for me?
Ah! I'm sitting on the couch of a teacher.
-Your mother is a teacher, too. -So what?
At least your mother doesn't work in the school.
I like your father. When I'm a teacher, I want to be like him.
-Hello! -Hello, grandma.
-Oh! Who is this pretty girl? -Tania.
Very good. I am Carmina Calduch.
Yes, I know. You are an actress. The one in the ad, right?
Baby, believe me, I made better things than that dip ad.
Of course, of course.
You're one of the best actresses in the country.
Oh yeah? And who are the others?
These people from the theater are a bit... nuts.
You can tell she gave birth to my weirdo father.
What's wrong?
-Yes. -Yeah. Liar!
Tell me. You're hiding something from me.
Let's see.
It seems... Well, it doesn't seem.
I like someone.
Bastard! You didn't tell me!
Don't good friends tell each other everything?
-Who? -I'm not going to tell you.
-Why? -Because you won't dance with me.
I can dance anytime. Tell me who you like!
-I'm not going to tell you. -Who? Tell me!
-No! -Tell me!
Girl, girl, that pillow is a souvenir from Cyrano.
Oh, sorry!
-I told you I like Marc. -Marc is a pig.
When I have a boyfriend, maybe I'm a little sow.
In fact, your volunteer teacher will come tomorrow, Eugeni Bosch.
I went ahead.
You must be like those cynical philosophers who believed
they could only achieve virtue out of society, right?
The thing is I am a teacher of Philosophy, you know?
I'll tell you an anecdote.
When Diogenes was a slave,
his owner asked, "What do you do best?"
Do you know what he said?
He said, "I know how to command. I order you to release me."
So, the owner granted him his freedom...
and made him his children's tutor.
Did you like it?
I guess you don't give a fuck,
but Eugeni won't tell you these anecdotes.
Very good. Goodbye. Stay there.
Work is piling up.
-Gorgeous. -It's obvious they got along.
Yes. Everyone was watching them in the park.
Pispa, Pispa, are you having fun with...?
What name are you going to call him?
-Descartes. -Descartes? The philosopher?
Oui, Descartes.
I like French sounds very much.
-Yes? -Yes.
-I lived in Paris. -In Paris?
-When my mother worked there. -Let's hear it. Speak French.
What do you want me to say? What am I supposed to talk about?
Philosophy. Descartes, for example.
Bonne. Je suis une chose qui pense.
I'm a thinking thing.
Qui doute, qui affirme, qui nie.
Who doubts,
who states...
Qui nie?
Who denies. Qui aime.
Wait. I'm going to feed the dogs.
Qui aime, qui veut, qui ne veut pas.
-Je pense, donque je suis. -I think, therefore I am.
That's messed up! You didn't tell me.
Hahaha.
Are you going to tell me who you like?
Yes, some day.
So? How are you?
What? Are we going to talk about something deep?
At the end of the day,
you have your father's sense of humor. Fine.
-Are you happy? -Yes. Got a little extra today.
What for?
He didn't talk much.
No, no. But he opened the door for me. It's a start.
Here.
A new mobile.
It's Chinese, a knockoff of the real one.
No, no, no, sorry. Good phones copy that.
It's better than the one you had, yes or no?
-Yes. -Good. You're welcome.
Thank you.
The peripatetic were students of Philosophy...
I know. I looked it up on Wikipedia.
Good night.
Dad.
I'm scared of what you can do in class.
Admit that you are weird...
complicated.
Yes, yes, yes. Yes, I'm complicated. Yes, yes.
But I'm still much better than the world you live in, son.
Everything is crap.
But I don't want you to fall into laziness nor pessimism.
I want you to get involved in things,
to be critical of what is around you.
Yes. I know it's horrible to think about these issues,
but I don't think teenagers
have only sex and getting drunk in their heads.
They also have fears, right?
They want to experience new things, but they are scared.
They are like amateur actors
before going on stage for the first time.
Oh, I don't know. Look...
you may fall in love someday and not be loved back.
Such is life. Not always
the one who likes you is the one you like.
Yes, Bruno. You have a complicated father or whatever...
But I'm the best teacher you'll ever had.
And, in time, you will see that I am right.
Patience. I know I'm difficult,
but you will have to take it with philosophy.
Not the school at your service.
Please, do not ignore rules anymore.
Who wants to cheat in the literary contest?
What is this guy saying? He's crazy!
-What's up? -I missed a period.
What?
It was sex and that's it. But you liked it, didn't you?
You know what I'm saying? Between us, it won't happen again.
I wrote some verses for the poem.
Will you read them to your father?
Very good.
You revved up the chicken coop!
Everything was very quiet until you arrived!
-Oh my God! -But didn't you say he wouldn't be here?
Give to me!
-Son... -Son, no!
And get dressed, heck! What are you doing with your balls?
Yes!
-Shut the fuck up. Back off. -Marc, leave it.
I know what's wrong.
What are you doing, you son of a bitch?
-Pol, hell! Enough! -Great!