Silence! Can you be quiet?
This assignment will count as a test
for the three who were suspended.
For the rest of you, it'll help your grades.
You can do it with a partner.
You must answer the following question with solid arguments:
If Aristotle were alive, would he have a Facebook profile?
Suspended students hand in the assignment tomorrow.
-The others can have three days. -That's not enough time.
Yes, it is. Silence! Attention, disciples.
I want to introduce a very special friend.
I'll flunk whoever writes his name wrong on the exam.
According to Schopenhauer,
man is a disgusting creature.
A man's desire of immortality is the desire of perpetuation
of a big mistake.
Sit up straight.
How can man be corrupt, a torturer and a murderer,
-can organize wars and genocides?
-The world is full of motherfuckers.
Yes, and why are we motherfuckers?
I have no idea.
Because our intelligence gives us the ability to harm.
According to Schopenhauer,
animals are not cruel to one another. But man is,
because you must be smart to harm others.
He said that all there is in the world are desires.
For example, we desire to have someone or something.
And, once we get tired of it,
we want something else. Why is that?
Where does that lead us,
when our desires are never satisfied?
Does anyone know?
-To frustration. -Go a little further.
-Suffering. -Exactly. Suffering.
Schopenhauer considered that life is essentially suffering.
Very nice, right?
Imagine going to a party with that idiot.
Schopenhauer.
And what do you want, disgusting creatures?
-I want a motorcycle. -Yeah.
-And you, Berta, what do you want?
-That you stop being my teacher.
You spend the whole class drawing on your table.
So what?
Taking notes on the table is so dirty.
I don't know. It's like
fucking your partner with a cat in the bed.
You can't leave in the middle of class.
I'll be right back.
He is watching you.
Laia, here you are. Have you seen Berta Prats?
No, no. Listen!
I called you yesterday, but you didn't answer.
Yeah, I couldn't reach the phone.
No, it's okay. I know
that you and I have no special relationship.
But sometimes I would like to do something different.
-Different? -Yes.
Can we talk later? I must go back, I left the students alone.
-Alone? -Yes.
Where is that girl?
Berta! Are you okay?
Yes, yes.
What are you doing out here?
Let's go inside.
Throw that away.
Come on.
But are you aware of what might have happened?
How could I know she would escape?
Toni, we are all little nervous.
Why don't you let me talk to her for a minute?
As you like.
I want this cleared up. Okay?
Let's see, Berta.
It's okay. I like you.
Give me a break.
I don't care whether you like me as a teacher or not.
But lately, I see that you are suffering.
Are you a psychologist now?
If you have a problem,
I think it'd be good if you talked to someone.
I don't know how Bruno can stand you.
The first day, I thought you were tough.
How old are you?
Why are you acting like a friend?
Do you want to fuck a student?
Do you think I want to fuck girls at your age?
Fresh meat.
I told you what I wanted to tell you.
-I just hope that you... -Fuck off!
Well, I can do the section one.
-You can do section two. -Hello.
If you prefer section one, I'll do the section two.
I also agree.
Does she like me? It's a pain. I haven't read it yet.
Don't tell her.
-No? -No.
Of course not, man.
What the fuck! I went out to the street, and Eugeni caught me.
She saw you with Marc, the other day.
Yes.
-Yeah? -Yeah.
-The protagonist is very authentic. -Very authentic.
And funny sometimes.
He is not funny.
Funny... What is funny, after all? But...
How about you and I pair up for the Philosophy assignment?
Unless you don't want to...
Yes, I do.
I'm free tomorrow afternoon, and there'll be no one home.
Good.
-I'll send you the address via WhatsApp. -Good. Good.
What should I have done?
-Tie Berta to a chair? -Do what we all do.
Notify the teacher on duty.
-Exactly. -He did tell me that.
You were not on duty.
I never imagined she would go out on the street.
You have no idea what they can do.
Responsibility is everything.
Something could have happened, Santi.
We'll open a disciplinary file for Berta.
Only for Berta?
I won't let this turn into a fight between two teachers.
At least she will pay for what she did.
You take it as a personal triumph.
Come on. You two, stop.
Toni, do you think this is enough?
That the problem is solved?
What matters the most is knowing what happens to that girl.
You worry so much about the students,
but you let them run away from school.
Thank you. Bye.
She made a fuss over nothing.
-Now Berta has an issue on her file. -What do you say?
-Fuck. -I swear.
I don't give a damn.
Don't overdo it. She is in a bad state.
Let's tell her to come. I feel bad.
Marc, if she comes, I'm leaving.
Yes, let's go.
I have to pick up my brother at school.
and Santi gave us homework.
Your parents control you a lot, huh?
Come on, catch him!
Hi.
You must have had a good day. You are happy.
Yes.
Did you have Philosophy today?
-Scho... -Schopenhauer?
That's him! He has a creepy face.
-Seriously? -Yes.
No wonder he is dating the English teacher.
What?
Yeah, he's dating Laia. Pol said so.
And is she good looking?
Yes, very beautiful.
Besides, she is very young. She could be his daughter.
She must be about 25 years old.
You can. But I don't need to know those things.
Okay.
There goes the girl.
She gets up from her chair,
walks across the room, leaves the class,
walks out of the school and almost gets herself killed.
-Does Berta get along with you? -Not really.
What kind of relationship do you have with Bruno?
Shut up!
Today, we learned about Schopenhauer.
He says humans are like porcupines.
When it's cold, they gather to get warm.
But if they get too close, they are pricked.
Then, they have to keep a certain distance. Understand?
You're there in the corner, alone, in the cold...
I'll tell Bruno to come see you.
I said no!
Let's walk a little more. Get up. Just a little more.
Get up and look up.
So we can badmouth the people passing by.
Can we go home? I feel bad.
Okay, let's go.
But I'll tell Bruno to come and see you tomorrow.
So, go have breakfast together.
He enjoys it. You can talk about politics. He likes that.
Why do I have to go exactly?
Honestly, I thought you'd like to see him.
He's a freak. That's why you get along with him.
Am I a freak?
Just look at the question you've put on the exam.
And the poster.
Shameful.
Go see him tomorrow and stop talking.
-How much will you pay me? -Zero.
You charge to be there. Why can't I?
You shouldn't do it for money.
You pay, I'll go. Let's say, ten euros?
Ten euros.
Jeez, going for money is ugly.
Who did I learn that from?
Hi.
Come in.
Gerard is not coming?
No, he'll come later. Over here.
Well, what happened?
What happened? Are you dating the English teacher?
No, it's not exactly like that.
What if I were? Yes, I'm not going to cheat on you.
We fucked, but it is over. But she still doesn't know that.
What a coward!
Now I see that you have two faces.
You are sniffing like a dog,
and you were sniffing the English teacher.
Damn, Gina.
With Laia, it was only sex.
You and I have a different relationship.
I've been already screwed up once.
My ex cheated on me for a long time with another woman.
I will break up with Laia like I planned to do.
Seriously, we haven't seen each other for days.
I'll tell her it's over.
-Hello! -Hey!
Goodness, what are you doing here?
Listen, Gerard, you'll be the first one to know.
Your mother and I...
we are organizing a trip to CosmoCaixa.
Yes, we are.
Cool.
But what does that have to do with Philosophy?
Galileo, Giordano Bruno...
I have been looking for the information of the museum...
do you know where the triptychs are?
When you find them, give it to Gerard and he'll give them to me.
We still have time to travel this semester.
-Sorry for making you come here for this. -It's okay.
You mother said that you used to go to a private school.
They'd go camping, do field trips,
travel at the end of the year...
More than anything to justify the price.
Goodbye, see you later.
The house is beautiful.
Sometimes he pisses me off. He has a way of seeing things...
I don't know. He is radical.
He is radical,
weird, selfish, self-seeking...
The teachers can't stand him. Eugeni wants to kill him.
You know?
You think he help you because he cares?
He does it for the money.
-I mean, not just for the money... -No, don't try to fix it.
Is it true that you like politics?
Politicians always say the same.
And what do they say?
If you don't know, why do you say they say?
If they cut off the head of those who steal,
the others would have to think twice.
There's new girl in class, right?
Gerard is head over heels.
You would agree, she is a bombshell.
Do you like her?
Yes.
Why are you so quiet?
You asked me: "Do you like her?"
-I don't know man. Yes, you can.
I'm shocked.
-If you're not, then fine. -Of course I'm not.
-Okay, no problem. You like girls.
I didn't say that to laugh at you.
It's okay.
If you keep making stupid remarks, don't come back to school.
-Hello. -Hello.
Hi.
-What is that? -Tea.
Listen, Laia.
I was thinking about what you told me.
I didn't answer a few calls because...
How can I put this?
I think I can't catch up with you anymore.
What do you mean by that?
I mean...
Let's see.
I don't think I'm the type that you should fall for.
Who told you that I am in love with you?
Yeah, but just in case...
Ah, just in case.
Yes, well...
Look.
I think you need someone who you can make plans with.
Someone who can give you children.
And I just had a vasectomy.
And...
Anyway, I think it's great that we could keep seeing each other,
but I think you needed to know that.
Okay. So...
Thank you very much for the information.
Let me think about it and I'll let you know.
Yes, of course.
I'm leaving.
Hello, Berta.
What happened?
Nothing. I fell down a staircase.
Does it hurt?
Yes.
Berta, what's wrong? You're very strange.
It doesn't matter. Forget it.
Come on, tell me.
-Promise me you won't tell anyone? -Sure.
My father got angry because
he says I don't do anything and get bad grades.
He got very angry.
He took my hand and twisted it.
But how are you? I'm freaking out.
I hate when these things happen.
Didn't you tell your mother? Didn't you defend yourself?
Don't tell anyone. Okay?
You should tell.
He got angry and then apologized.
Okay.
He twisted her arm?
Yes. It seems like he got angry and started yelling
and ended up...
Son of a bitch.
Oh, my. Poor girl.
I feel sorry for her.
It's strange, because her father is always traveling.
-He had a fight with her mother. -Yes.
I know her father and I know he has a bad temper.
-But hurting her... -He hurt her a lot.
We should tell the teachers.
No. I think she is the one who must tell them.
We have to tell them. They could help her.
No, Joan. We have to wait.
Yes, it is better to wait for her to do tell them.
What's up?
Honestly, do you think people notice me?
No.
What a strain on yesterday's meeting.
-Sorry if you got nervous, but that... -No, no.
Besides, sometimes I admit that I annoy him.
No, no. But I understand you.
I mean, when necessary...
you must be firm. Right?
I am firm, but I'm also friendly, right?
Yes, very much.
-At least I think so. -Yes.
I mean...
In other words, you are firm but...
-Sensitive? -Yes.
Do you like a bar called Flagstaff?
-Is it a country music bar? -Yes.
-Do you like country music? -Yes, a lot.
Oh, yeah?
-What is wrong with country music? -It's just that...
If you want, I invite you. Shall we have a beer this afternoon?
Is that...
It's that...
-I have things to do. -Sure. Yes, yes.
-Yes, yes. -We can go another day?
-Yes. Very well. -Yes. Great.
One moment, please.
Remember you have a test next week.
-Yes. -On what?
Bruno, I just said: lesson six and seven.
Man, today is my day.
You fuck her today.
What did I tell you?
-I don't know. But something will happen. -Come here.
You must be confident with her.
Berta.
I heard what your father did.
-Shit, man. I told Marc not to tell...
-I think you should do something.
I can't, I'm afraid.
I need some time.
As you wish.
See you tomorrow.
Berta.
Why did you tell her?
Damn, Berta. This is very serious.
I did it to help you.
Tania is a nice girl. She encouraged me.
So did I.
I know how these family problems are.
And I hate seeing you like this.
I am very lonely in the afternoon until my father comes home.
How about your sister and your mother?
They always come home very late.
Well, then...
if you want, I could go one of these days
to keep you company.
have to pick up my little brother at school.
I know. It's complicated.
What a view!
Damn, how come you live so far from school?
When we moved, my parents
split up and my mother stayed in the house.
My parents are also divorced.
But I take the opportunity to get money from my father.
What are you talking about?
-Two hundred euros a month or so. -Two hundred euros?
-What? He is a doctor and has money. -My father is a doctor, too.
Really?
-You and I have things in common. -Let's do the assignment.
Right.
Berta...
are you sure you want this?
want it to look like I'm taking advantage of you.
What's wrong, Marc? You're acting weird.
My father hit me a few times, too.
Oh, my.
Do you remember in eighth grade,
when someone stole my video game?
-Yes, the small one. -The PSP.
My parents forbade me to take it to school,
but I ignored them.
And when it disappeared,
my father hit me a lot.
I was 14.
Then, my mother left him.
I still don't know who stole my PSP.
There's always stealing in school.
-Do you still see him? -Sometimes.
He has a crazy business that always goes wrong.
He is a failure.
You're always so happy.
Berta, I'm fine.
People think that I am funny.
Yes, I am, but I am also sensitive.
We won't do anything.
I mean it.
No one should know about this. Let's not tell Tania.
What about Tania?
Nothing.
Yes.
-Are you leaving now? -Yes, why?
Nothing.
I thought about what you told me,
that you can't have children.
I don't want to have kids.
So, I don't have any problem with that.
We can continue seeing each other.
And since you had a vasectomy, this shouldn't be a problem.
Instead of being a man and leaving me,
you made up this shit about not being able to have kids.
What for? So I would break up with you?
I might be a little naive, but I'm not an idiot.
-How did she take it? -Well.
I don't know where you and I are going.
We'll go wherever we want.
Do you think we can go to CosmoCaixa only for sex?
Yes. Gerard already knows about the trip to the museum.
Then, we have to do it.
What is the dog doing here?
-No, get it away from here, Gina. -Why? This is Rufo.
No, it is just that...
Come here.
-You do understand, right? -Yes, I understand.
-But I don't want to take him away. -Don't you see him every day?
You rather make me uncomfortable than taking him away?
If you're so uncomfortable, leave!
Very well. I'll leave you guys here, chatting about your stuff.
Bye.
We can read it again, to see if there is something missing.
Right, yes.
Thank you for introducing me to "The Steppenwolf".
What else do you like?
What else do I like...
To eat.
I like paella, too. See? You and I...
is that I like you.
I...
I like you a lot.
When I saw you going to class, the first day...
I thought...
What is that?
A bull?
Yes, that's my grandfather's, from when he was young.
Oh, your grandfather was a bullfighter?
Yes, he used to fight in his hometown, Andalusia.
But now he's old and the poor man can't do it anymore.
Poor man?
The bulls he killed are the miserable ones, right?
I like bullfighting festivals. Bullfighting is an art.
You're kidding.
No.
-You think torturing animals is an art.
-Gerard, can we continue working, please?
No. It's shocking that you're saying something like that.
I don't understand.
It's art, tradition, culture.
What you don't understand?
-How many bulls did he kill? -What is your point?
They take the bulls there and kill them as if it were a show.
Do you think it's normal?
You're not normal. Leave.
-What? -I don't want you talking to me like that.
So, you have to leave my house.
He doesn't want to leave the room.
I don't know what is wrong with him.
He had a bad day.
Your son came over this morning. Do you think they argued?
Who knows what Bruno told him.
I have to go.
Go in peace.
Let me know if it gets tricky.
-Bye. -Bye.
What are you doing here?
What's that face? What's up?
-I told you not to ask Bruno to come. -Why? What did he say?
What happened? Did he insult you?
-Did he laugh at you? -No, he's not the problem.
-I'm your teacher. -Are you?
You do whatever you want.
You take advantage of me being sick and deceive me.
I'm sick, fucker. Don't you understand?
You're sick, but you don't want to see a shrink.
I do my best for you to have friends.
Why should I have friends when you don't have any?
You don't know how to interact with people.
You think you are too good and that others are shit.
Maybe other people don't need you.
The teachers at school can't stand you.
Even your son criticizes you.
And I feel sorry for scoundrels!
-No, I didn't tell him that you dance,
and I am tired of this topic.
When I finish school, we'll see about that. But not now.
That's not what frightens you.
You have to take off your mask.
What scares you is not the fact that he knows you dance, but...
-You know what. -No, I...
Dancing is my thing.
You stick with the dance thing again? How hard can it be?
Why the fuck do you care about what people say?
You have to think that you're not the only one.
No worries, Bruno! The world is full of fags.
-Will you deny the evidence? -Dad, you are crazy!
You shouldn't give a shit about what they think of you.
If you like guys...
Dad, I forbid you to talk about this with anyone in this town!
Listen to me, dammit. You shouldn't care...
Shut up, shut up. No, no, no!
Oh, my God!
What did you think? That I wouldn't know?
The school called me.
You know that they will
open a file and suspend you for three days?
What were you thinking?
I will not appeal like the previous times.
This time, you take the responsibility.
I'm exhausted.
I spent the day at the salon and taking care of your sister,
taking her to the training, the competitions...
At least, Cristina gives me joy.
She wins competitions and still gets good grades.
But I come here and I see the big picture.
Did you make your bed today? No.
I already knew before entering your room.
I gave up on you.
You ran away from school!
Don't you feel ashamed? I do.
I called the principal:
"Elsa, calm down. That's what they do at this age".
"Bullshit".
This is not an age thing.
This is my daughter, giving me a hard time.
You only give us trouble. Always with that bitter face.
I'll make dinner.
If you want, we will
continue going out every afternoon for a walk.
You're right.
I have no friends and I want you to have some.
I'm contradictory. What can I say?
Friendship is overrated.
You can call anyone a friend.
For me, being alone has a double advantage.
You can be yourself and don't have to put up with anyone.
But I guess you already know that, right?
That's why I brought you a gift.
Bye.
What is it, in Philosophy,
when everything goes wrong and life is a piece of shit?
Adolescent recalcitrant egocentricity.
I like a girl who likes bullfighting.
Is this obsession with animals a family thing?
I like animals a lot.
Why are you looking at me like that? My favorite animal are dogs.
Mine is a steak.
If possible, with chips.
She likes bullfighting.
When you're in love, you accept each other's differences.
I even think that you will
She is pretty and mature.
Like a woman?
Yes, she's no longer a little girl.
Her rhythm, her beat is more like a woman's.
She thinks like a woman.
-Hello. -Excuse me.
It's okay, Marc. Gerard is leaving.
After giving me an overdose of silliness.
What's up, Vilaseca?
Will this end soon?
I know what your father did.
-It just happened once. -I'll talk to Toni.
I'll will do what should be done in these cases.
The school supports you. I understand you're afraid.
I don't fucking care.
It's a lie. No one hurt me. I did it myself.
You see how you are suffering?
You're a little girl who is trying to get attention.
Someone hurt you and you keep silent.
Who is hurting you, Berta?
Don't tell this to anyone, please.
Open the book to page 32.
Gerard, read it, please.
"The pastoral novel is one of the fundamental kinds
of prose of the Renaissance fiction in Spain.
Girl, my father knows.
It is characterized for its
idealizing content and neo-platonic aesthetics,
It tells us the amorous misadventures
We talk later. You'll go nuts.
of educated and idealized shepherds in an idyllic nature."
Stop.
Tania.
-Give me the phone, please. -I...
-You know that's not allowed in class. -Damn, Santi!
What's wrong with you?
She already put it away. You don't need to take it from her.
Really?
Rules are rules, Tania. Come on.
Keep going.
"The main characters tell their love... "
Come on.
You have the keys to the school, right?
I love dogs and you hate them.
I'm considerate and I want to make things easy.
Next time, I'll lock the dog in a room.
Well, I'll lock my mother in the bathroom.
And what do we do with our children?
Our children?
Our children are in class right now.
And this room is empty.
No, not here.
-You're crazy, I said no. -Yes, I'm crazy and I turn you on.
I locked the door.
-Oh, my! How old are we? -Seventeen.
We should be in Literature class, but we left. Nobody saw us.
We hid from the janitor and the director, running down the hall.
We never have time alone.
We saw this empty office and we shut ourselves inside.
We are seventeen and we are alone, at last.
Okay, I went too far, right?
But it was nice to be with you.
And I get along with you. You know that.
We may not agree in this case, but we do in others.
Can we forget about that and keep doing the assignment?
Please? For real.
All right.
-But with two conditions. -Yes.
We do it at school and never talk about bulls again.
Not a word, okay.
There is something I would like to tell you.
I have what?
The way you talk, you know?
Girls in class are more like children.
Right.
For Schopenhauer, the only way to fight the desire
was to opt for nothing.
Nothingness is empty, the absence of desire.
For him, it was the only way to fight suffering. Understand?
He believed that to achieve complete happiness,
one should renounce every kind of desire.
Come in. Hello, Berta.
I was in the bathroom.
Come in.
How's your arm?
All right.
Take off your jacket, you'll be more comfortable.
As I was saying,
Schopenhauer thought that to avoid suffering
you had to give up desires, But how can we do that?
We always desire something.
Dear bipeds, you must try
to not be infected by Schopenhauer's pessimism.
But I threw a question
in the air: whenever we get what we desire,
why do we desire something else?
Schopenhauer said that it was the only way out of suffering.
But if you have no desires, you still suffer, right?
You might feel isolated.
You see everyone smiling and knowing what they want.
What if you don't know what you want?
What if...
you wake up and don't want to get out of bed?
That happens to some people.
Then what?
For those who feel that way,
it would do well for them
to reconnect with the peripatetics' teacher,
Aristotle.
He said that hope is a waking dream.
Is it normal for Bruno to use the phone during the class?
You're funny, aren't you?
-I'm not laughing. -Fuck it.
Go see the teacher on duty.
This was broken on purpose.
Listen, Joan, do you know anything about dad's model?
-What have you got here? -A piercing.
-He has nothing to do with it.
-A teacher, friends with the students...
I wanted to do this! Nobody told me to!
At least he understands more than you!
How did you come up with the idea of the CosmoCaixa getaway?
-It was her. -It was him.
You have a boyfriend.
No.
Mom, don't lie to me. I know you do.
since I screwed up with his father.
I'm not selling the bike. So leave me alone.
I kill myself working...
Will you start with that, again?
They cut the electricity.
You are in love.
You don't need to tell me anything, but you're in love.
When you said:
I know it's very easy to tell you to forget that person.
But if the person ignores you,
then it's the best thing you can do.